It is time... for trains.
Hopefully.
I've been building up this train thing in my mind for so long.
Today, surely, it will happen.
Cheers, guys.
I got some iced tea now.
I'll tell you what.
Losing three games in a row in deadlock just before definitely woke me up.
Now I'm in the midday phase.
Which means I'm gonna be even more ready.
A skeleton popped out!
God, this iced tea is so good.
I can't believe it's zero sugar.
That's wild to me.
Okay, let's let the lags dissipate.
This looks like a crazy mess right now.
Okay.
Guys.
We got this one.
Sturdy sheet.
Also, I'm barefoot.
Train casing!
That sounds good to me.
Train schedule.
Damn.
Let's do some more Powered Obsidian stuff.
Oh, we also have this one.
Bonk!
It's beautiful.
I'm gonna do this.
No, wait.
We're gonna do it properly.
Yeah!
Oops!
That's too much.
Oh, did we run out of lava?
Ah, okay.
I see how it is.
I see your stance.
We got the flying bitches.
That's okay.
I'm not afraid of them.
I've got berries.
Oh, also, I installed the resource pack.
Made by...
Forgive me.
Forgot the name.
Someone on the Discord graciously decided to make a resource pack that hopefully will now play creative music.
We'll see how it goes.
Um...
I have a shield, right?
I should have a shield.
Maybe I don't.
That's fine.
Don't need a shield.
I needed some...
Uh...
Lava!
And I wouldn't mind actually bringing more buckets.
Just to bring more lava.
I don't need all this right now.
Don't need any of this.
Yo!
Wow!
Why am I so on edge right now?
Wheat flour?
I feel like that should go in here.
Stick.
And torches.
Inventory has been cleaned.
Milord.
Uh, actually we put this in here.
Yeah!
Let's go get some lava!
Oh!
And...
Powdered obsidian.
Let's pull this in again.
Let's just make as much as we can of this.
Watch it come up.
Squeezed in there.
It's gonna go up via another set of...
Uh...
There it is.
Look.
Oh, we even got it back.
In you go.
Love watching this work.
So satisfying creating something like this and then watching it just work, you know?
We got it back again!
Infinite powder.
The day of slaughter.
Which is good, because now we really need three buckets of this.
51 flint.
Oh!
Let's go feed the animals.
Can't forget that.
The day of slaughter is fast approaching.
Look how many animals I have!
Who's shooting?
Oh, you bastard!
Trying to kill my flock!
Get out of here.
I should go to bed.
Too many animals and creatures at night.
Okay.
I actually kinda wanna go slaughter them now.
Dude, this obsidian lasts forever!
We're gonna get it again.
Watch.
The one time I make a prediction.
Crazy.
Lava time.
I'm gonna run out of lava at some point.
But I guess we have the nether.
There's no shortage of lava.
There we go.
That should do it.
So I think we can say that one lava bucket equals two sturdy sheets.
Don't even wanna fight that guy.
Also, the weird thing is, when I eat these berries, it's almost like my food is going down faster when I exercise.
There we go!
And it gets sucked in.
Did it work?
It didn't work.
There we go!
Wow, it really is just two squeezes of lava, huh?
That's all I get.
The sound I make, though.
Alright, this is not the most efficient way to do it, but...
Yes!
I don't know if I need more than eight for whatever I'm about to do.
We'll find out.
Oh, shit.
Let me figure out what I can make with it, then.
So I need a brass casing, I believe.
A casing...
Train casing.
Okay.
Let's make it!
Surely that will unlock a bunch of things.
I will also work on that, I think.
Because I do wanna make this digging machine mobile and steerable.
Brass casing...
I may not...
I do have.
Nice.
I mean, we can start with one.
Look at that.
Locomotive age!
Oh my god!
Oh!
That's all kinds of shit!
Nice!
Hello?
Is it in here?
Train trapdoor!
Dope.
Schedule...
Train observer?
Train signal.
And a train station.
Wait, didn't I already...
Maybe that's a different way.
Oh, that's a different way I'm making it, I guess.
Train door.
Block of experience.
Huh.
Well...
I gotta be honest...
Well, okay.
Let's not...
Panic too early.
I'm gonna make all of these and then...
Potentially that will unlock something that seems useful for trains.
Like, all of this seems like...
For the tracks.
But what about my actual train?
You know?
Let's go murder some animals.
I think it's time.
I really need some food.
It is time.
And it shall be cows.
Oh, he ran off.
Don't run from...
Bro!
Die, please.
How did you survive the crit?
Imagine how...
Panic-y it must be to be in here while I just come in here and murder them.
Let's also take some...
No, let's leave the sheep for now.
Nah.
I don't discriminate.
Kill everyone.
Not everyone.
We're gonna still feed them, of course.
But this is a nice payday.
Now, realistically, I think it would make more sense to first shear these sheep and then kill them, but...
Nah, too late.
I'm here.
I'm doing it.
The food shortages are finally over, brothers!
Only meat from now on.
Back on the menu!
Get out of here.
How much did they get?
29...
Oh...
It's not actually that much.
I was hoping for more, but this is a good start.
Oh, that's a blast furnace.
I need a better way to...
fuel this.
Hmm.
I do wonder if there's a way to get infinite lava.
You know, like...
Making a lava lake like that, apparently, is not good enough.
Because it will run out.
Finally, some good food.
Oh, my gosh.
I have been craving these steaks!
For approximately, like, 10 hours in the game.
I should probably make a couple more of these train thingies.
And then use them for something.
Train?
Let's make a train station.
Need a compass for that.
Not even sure if I have that.
Doesn't look like it.
Compass is redstone, I know that.
And I think iron?
Iron and redstone, that's it.
Dude, my memory's impeccable.
Train...
Station...
Let's ponder on that.
In fact, it made two of them.
Select the train track, then place the station nearby.
Stations are the waypoints of your track network.
Okay!
To create a new train, open the UI and switch to assembly mode.
This seems like a pretty deep system.
During assembly, no scheduled trains will approach this station.
Okay.
Wait, the trains are automated or what?
This is what I need!
Create new bogeys by using train casings on tracks!
Bogeys.
Click the track again to cycle between bogey designs.
Attach blocks with the help of super glue.
Okay.
Oh,
dude!
This is sick!
Assembled trains will move faster if they can find fuel in assembled chests or barrels.
Okay.
So like, I guess, coal.
Fuel stored in vaults will not be consumed by the train.
Okay.
So that's more for transportation of goods.
Every train requires train controls on board.
Oh!
Okay.
So we gotta make that.
An optional second one allows departure from stations in both directions.
Wait!
Oh!
Maybe I'm not allowed to steer the train then.
It's just gonna go through...
Or from train station to train station.
Open the station UI and confirm the assembly process.
Oh!
Oh my god, that looks so good.
Trains can be disassembled back into blocks at stations only.
I'm assuming with the wrench.
When used on a station, maps will add a labeled marker at the location.
A labeled marker?!
You mean like on a map?
Or what?
Assembled trains can be relocated to nearby tracks using the wrench.
Okay, I figured.
There's more.
Schedules can be used to provide drivers with a destination.
Wait, so you just put in like...
Oh!
That's what the labels are for, I guess.
You say, go to Amityville.
You know?
And then it goes that way.
Comparators will receive a signal whenever a train is present.
From the train station.
Okay.
Turn it around.
Mind that a station can only be approached from the indicated direction.
Ah.
This is gonna take some time getting used to here, I think.
Stations can also be used to assign new schedules automatically?
What?!
The schedule placed on a station will automatically copy itself to present trains.
Uh...
Why...
What's the point?
As opposed to manual scheduling, the drivers will not take the item with them.
Okay...
That last part doesn't make sense to me.
But...
Maybe the rest does.
Let's just try it, shall we?
We got tracks.
We got train casings.
We have a train station.
Um...
I'm going to disassemble this.
I do want the train station to be right here, actually.
I think this is a good spot.
Wait, can I...
Ah!
Ha ha ha ha.
Much better.
Can I do it with everything?
No.
No dirt, huh?
Fill these up.
Okay, man, are you ready?
I think the train station should be right outside my house here.
Like here.
Successfully bound to target a track.
Gotcha!
Maybe it needs to be...
Wait, what?
Hold on.
What did that say?
Create new bogeys by using train casings on tracks.
Oh, wait!
Assembly mode!
Ah!
No bogeys!
Use train casing on highlighted tracks to create bogeys.
Remove bogeys by breaking the block on top.
Build carriages attached to one or two bogeys each.
Okay.
Let me actually extend this track a little bit.
Oh!
Here we go!
Oh, wait.
I can't do that over here.
Okay, wait.
I gotta see this again.
Yeah?
Click the track again to cycle between bogey designs.
Uh-huh.
Let's stick with this one for now.
How come I don't have this sort of color over here as they have on the drawing?
That doesn't make sense.
Like, look at this.
See the blue?
Okay.
Use... yeah.
Click the track again.
Attach blocks with the help of super glue.
Okay, let's just do that, I guess.
Maybe I can...
Need to move it?
Push.
Oh!
Fuck me!
It's over here.
I gotta see this again, man.
But...
Are...
Are these connected then, or what?
Wait.
Remove this.
How did I remove that?
Cycle...
I don't know what bogey means.
Like, apparently, this is a bogey?
To me, bogeys are like enemy fighters in the sky.
Two bogeys.
Use train casing on highlighted tracks to create bogeys.
Remove bogeys by breaking the block...
Okay, breaking the...
Whoops.
Wait, is it working?
Let me break that.
Go back into assembly.
Are they connected now?
Assemble train.
Assembly failed.
No structure attached to bogey one.
Okay.
So there needs to be a structure.
I see.
Let's start with two bogeys.
One there and one there.
Turn them into that.
And
then...
What, they just put some blocks on?
Or what?
How do they do that?
Let's just make it simple.
Let's just do that at first.
See if that works.
Now we have attached something, right?
Now we need glue.
And the way they showed that in the drawing...
Just make the whole thing.
Because I can't.
Maybe I need to put blocks on each side?
I don't know.
Let's just find out.
This extends over here.
Not really.
Attach at least one forward-facing train controls block.
Oh yeah, right, right, right.
That's also something I needed.
Train controls.
Oh shit.
Can I even make that?
Train...
Maybe it's just controls.
Contraption controls?
Is there a difference?
Let's see in here.
Yeah, we don't even know what that is.
Damn.
So I guess we still can't make trains.
Fuck me.
Okay.
Look at the achievements.
Let's just follow the thread here.
Trains, trains.
Okay, assemble your first train.
We can't do that yet.
Assemble a steam whistle to your train.
Maybe a train schedule.
That seemed easy to make, right?
Train...
Schedule...
Oh, I even have one sturdy sheet left.
I don't think I have paper.
Oh, man.
Paper requires sugar cane and sugar cane.
Wait.
Ah, damn.
I don't have any.
Okay, let's try something else.
We can try...
Steam whistle doesn't look like it's gonna do much.
We can try the precision mechanism, I guess.
Fine-tune your contraption.
Like, it's all connected here, right?
Produce more than a thousand train tracks with the same mechanical press.
Create a train with at least six carriages.
What does it take to make a steam whistle?
Also, don't I have this one?
I'm pretty sure I have that.
Hey, I got it!
Okay, never mind then.
Um...
Yeah, I mean, let's just start from one end.
Let's make a precision mechanism.
I've been wanting to do that anyway for a while.
Okay, so, poke, poke, poke.
Small, big, nuck.
Got it.
And what was the input?
Precision...
Just golden sheets, okay.
Five times in a row.
Don't I have a bunch of hands?
I've got some hands.
Nah, these belong in food, I guess.
Oh, my food!
We're not even ready.
Need more wood.
I'm just gonna burn all this wood.
I don't care.
Nope.
I don't need all these buckets.
Rest is good.
We have a big, we have a small.
Then we needed the nuggets.
Oh, don't I even have nuggets?
Press...
Shit.
Oh wait, I can make them.
I have normal iron.
Okay.
I think I'm ready to do this.
We're gonna make this.
We're just gonna make a bunch of shit now.
And hopefully the train controls fall out.
We actually have a little process over here already.
Yeah.
This one.
What?
No.
No, no, no, no, no.
Yes.
Over-stressed!
Gosh dang it.
Oh no.
Let's empty this.
Oh my god.
I wish there was a way to just...
easily...
pick these up, you know?
Aren't they at least gonna go in there?
Okay.
We gotta stop that.
No more slaps.
Stop it.
So, the first one needed...
small cock.
Next one big.
Last one nug.
And then input was...
golden sheets.
I have those.
Kinda wanna expand my house.
I forgot what I came back for.
Oh yeah.
That's...
all I have?
I have one?
Do we have the presser?
Pain.
I need one!
Did I use them all?
Oh...
It's okay.
We can probably just press it over here.
I manually just put it on the line, right?
And it should work.
Might go like this.
What?
Oh, it's not connected.
Right.
We're gonna have to choose.
Let's start by doing this.
We have one.
Oh!
This needs to go again and again.
Fuck it.
We're gonna do this manually here.
What happened there?
Heard that sound?
Can you just please let me work in peace?
Like, is it... is it just not bright enough here or what?
There's torches everywhere.
Leave me alone.
Okay, here we go.
Let's see.
What's happening?
Oh, we ran out of cocks!
That's not good.
Cog.
And go.
It's almost done.
Come on.
We need small and big cocks.
Oh no.
Ah, but wait.
That's gonna come...
What does it take?
Gimme...
I'll go back.
I need casings.
I hate being short just exactly what I need.
Shafts.
Cog.
More.
More wood.
Really low on wood these days.
There we go.
This thing better work!
Precision mechanism.
Okay, small cock.
Go.
Big one.
Yeah!
We made it!
We all...
Oh shit!
We're unlocking...
Oh!
Holy fuck!
That's a lot!
Wow!
This has been totally worth.
Factory gauge.
What?
Rotation speed controller.
Damn.
Hold on, I need a...
I need this.
Let's see what else.
Train controls!
There it is!
Train casing and lever.
Yes, sir!
We're making it right now.
We're inching closer and closer to this damn train, CJ!
All I had to do was build it.
Uno lever!
Train...
Controls!
Let me ponder on that.
Accelerate and steer the train using movement keybinds!
But how do you steer a train on a track?
Isn't it literally on tracks?
You can...
Okay, we can tune to top speed.
Hold space to approach a nearby station.
Oh?
Trains can only be disassembled back into blocks of stations.
Say no more, fam!
I'm on it!
Why can't I...
Attach at least one forward-facing train controls block.
Wait...
Is it...
Is this not forward-facing?
What?!
Why?!
What about now?
No?!
Put it here.
I'm not missing superglue!
What is the problem?
Maybe it needs to be like that?
No way, that seems super janky.
Wait, let me try something else.
Let me try from here...
Here...
I don't understand what's wrong.
What am I missing?
Okay, yeah.
Maybe I need to build it sideways?
Like they show in the picture?
Let me get some slaps.
It's just weirdly and oddly specific though.
I'm gonna copy the exact fucking design.
There.
Now...
Unless this needs to be right on that...
Hold on, let me check if that's the case.
Okay, yeah, he does put it there.
Ah, nevermind.
Nevermind.
Okay.
Is this not forward-facing?
Okay, let's try and glue it.
Remove this.
Yeah.
And then this one?
Surely this will work.
No?!
Okay, it's gotta be the other side then.
Now glue it.
What am I doing?
Wait...
What am I missing here?
I'm fucking losing my mind!
This is so unintuitive.
It's crazy.
Done that.
Maybe I need two bogies.
Assemble trains will move faster if they find fuel in assemble chests or barrels.
Maybe they need to have fuel before they can even be assembled?
Yeah.
I have no idea what's missing.
Let me try and put this in the center.
And glue it.
In fact, we're gonna do exactly what they did.
Nope.
Okay, so what about the other direction?
Okay.
Disassembled the whole fucking thing.
Okay, so it's clearly this way, right?
So the controls need to be facing that way.
Got it.
Make a train.
Use train casing on highlighted tracks to create bogies.
Got it.
Done.
Now.
Connect these fucking blocks.
Just like in the picture.
Make sure it's all glued.
In fact, we're gonna double check all this.
Put the train control on.
And it's going that way.
We confirm that.
Glue it all together.
Actually, start from the top maybe.
Shit.
Stop, stop, stop.
Why won't it...
There we go.
No.
For some reason it won't deselect now.
There we go.
Oh, shit.
It's so finicky, man.
Come on.
Click spot.
I have no idea why it didn't work before.
I did the exact same thing.
First train.
Okay.
So, now.
If I click this.
Now controlling first train.
Oh!
Very nice.
Nice.
Oh no.
My armor is overlapping the thing so I can't read it.
Hold...
Uh...
Space to approach track station.
Sweet.
And then to let go of it, I right click.
Okay, okay, okay.
Sweet.
Now I wanna make more.
So...
Can I just go back into assembly?
There we go.
Now we put one here.
The question is how to connect these.
Maybe there's like a specific train connector or link or something.
Train signal.
In the little image...
They showed them just next to each other like this.
Oh, I guess I just glued all together?
Into one?
No way, right?
I mean, that could be the thing.
They drive off, don't they?
They...
Okay, they both drive.
I guess maybe they're just sort of connected because it's like...
Being assembled together?
So wait, there's no way to just...
Like, physically connect them?
That's weird.
So wait, if I now do this...
Ah!
Okay, it didn't show up in the fucking animation!
There we go!
Look at that!
Ho-hoi!
Very nice.
Okay, now we're on the...
Oh, I messed it up.
There we go.
Right click.
Good.
Also, I'm somehow level 29.
Right, because of the experience from the crushing wheel.
Um...
Well, this is a nice looking train.
We can make it look nicer though.
I guess.
Let's, uh...
Let's actually make some tracks.
I will make a turn here and go towards the factory.
Too sharp, really?
Well, that's a big boy tree.
Now we wanna go down, I guess?
And that should just work.
Hey dude.
I'm making trains.
Actually, let me try something.
Maybe I want this...
Oh, okay, you can't actually control the steepness of that.
Wait, this is gonna go straight into it though.
I don't know if that's a good idea.
Can I make like...
Exactly.
That.
I guess we need some kind of switch then.
Maybe you can actually steer it a little bit towards left or right when you're going.
Get rid of these trees.
I hate the rain.
I hate the night.
Get rid of it.
Okay, let's see if this works.
Is it gonna go through the blocks?
It is, but I'm not.
Interesting.
The funny thing is, it's going without fuel, it seems.
So, let's just, you know, free train.
Free transportation.
Okay, let's see if we can turn left here.
Oh, cool!
Let me just keep going straight, see if that works.
Oh my god!
Amazing.
Very cool.
Uh, can I just get rid of that?
There we go.
Can't have these growing on the tracks now.
That's no bueno.
Okay, you definitely use a lot of train tracks for this.
No surprise.
Oh my...
You know what?
I need a hand crank and a drill.
I've had it with these goddamn trees.
Let's resort to industrialization on that one.
I've got the crank.
Now...
Oh, I need a saw, not a drill.
I may not even have that, actually.
Iron and casing.
Also, my arm...
Is slipping all over the place.
Which is a funny sentence, but it's true.
Sheets...
And normal iron.
Green, put in there.
Let's also cook some more food.
Level 30!
Let's enchant a pickaxe.
Uh, we need a fresh one.
First thing we do right now.
Ooh, that's amazing!
Yes!
Holy shit!
Guys, fortune smiles upon us.
That is huge!
Wow!
Best enchantment ever!
Enchantment!
Okay, I was making something...
Uh, involving this...
Oh yeah!
Uh, saw!
What?
Saw...
Here we go.
I'm gonna saw it and crank it.
Much faster.
Actually, it may not be faster for small trees like this, but whatever.
It's still satisfying.
So, the idea now, guys, is that we're gonna make trains connect the world.
Getting some good wood out of this too, which is something I need.
I've been running low on that lately.
Okay, that's a good start.
So, I guess we're just gonna go this way.
Train's gonna go through the mountain over here.
Yo!
Oh!
Let's put drills in front of the train!
Ah, wait, wait!
Uh, maybe there's...
Hmm.
I do wonder if we can automatically place these tracks similar to our old digging machine.
What?
No, no, no, no, uh...
Oh, I guess I need to...
Wait, what the...
Oh, I can control it like...
Oh, that's funky.
Bro, that's...
That's weird.
I can do that.
I'm trying to park it.
Stopped controlling and...
Oh, I guess I was far away.
Do I need to be on it for this to work?
There we go.
So, now it's here.
We're gonna click...
Disassemble.
Fuck, what did I do?
Okay, good.
Naive.
Let's try.
Okay, that worked so far.
I'm assuming this is just gonna work similar to any other contraption.
Okay.
And obviously we would need a drill in front, but this is just to test if this even works.
Oh, it's working!
Look how fast it's going up and down.
It's a little janky and it works.
It works, but it is definitely a little, you know.
Oh, oh, oh!
I'm stuck!
I can't move!
Oh, my God!
Information about train...
Wait, what, what?
A carriage has reached the end of its track.
Okay, that was janky as hell.
Wait, didn't I just give it a bunch of tracks?
Or what happened to those?
Oh, yeah, look!
I got 14 now.
I put it in, there.
Okay, it is working.
Oh, it's a little janky the way that works.
I gotta be honest there.
But maybe if I put it a little further in front, it's gonna be less janky.
Because right now it's...
I think it's kind of fighting.
You know, like it's riding right on the thing that's being placed.
So just having it a little further in front could maybe be the way to forward here.
How do I...
Oh, God, this is...
I need a way to get up on this train!
Shit!
Okay, that works.
Back up!
There we go.
Now...
Let's move this.
Oh, I guess we gotta do that.
Okay, we're learning here.
What do we put in front?
It needs to look okay as well, you know?
Like, there's definitely some style here.
I feel like we need to adhere to.
Let's use and a side casing, actually.
Like that.
Okay.
There you go.
Glue it all.
This should be better, I think.
Let's see.
Dude, it feels amazing!
The trains are so cool!
Oh, wait.
I gotta get up on the train.
Still a little janky.
And now I'm weirdly stuck here.
Oh, no.
Oh, I can just press control?
Oh, much better!
Okay, okay, nice.
Sweet.
I mean, it works.
So I guess it doesn't matter if we have it in front here or...
Actually, I do wanna just double check real quick.
So if I go like this...
Ah, shit.
I gotta bring it all the way back to modify it.
Hmm.
Eat my meat.
Fine.
The silly song is just fucking unstoppable.
It's apparently the only song that exists in this game.
Okay.
There.
So we don't need to do this.
We can move that in front here.
Good.
Tracks on it?
Oh, we used them all.
That's actually a problem.
Let's get the drills.
16 drills.
It's kinda solid.
The thing that worries me, though.
Yeah, I can't dig...
I can't drill further down!
Shit.
It ain't gonna work.
Actually, it could work.
As long as these drills are in front of the tracks.
So if I were to do this...
There it is!
Obviously we can't go backwards, then.
Or can we?
Oh, I'm almost out of superglue here.
Slime ball, sheets, and nuggets.
All the things I don't have.
Do I... I don't even have a slime ball.
Oi!
I stole a cookie.
Slima.
Well, guess that's not happening.
Uh, I've...
Where the fuck do we get a slime ball?
Maybe in here?
Uh...
Slim...
Green...
Goddammit.
Okay, I guess we gotta find some green dude somewhere!
This is kind of a problem.
This is not like...
That's not easy to do.
They are not just everywhere, you know?
I feel like these belong in here.
Well, there goes a stop to my enjoyment there.
Shit!
Farming.
Nope.
This one?
Just fill up the inventory here.
What a bummer!
That's fine.
Infinity...
Um...
Okay, so what is next?
I guess we gotta go find some green goop.
Or...
Couldn't we use honey for this?
Honey glue!
Okay.
Honey and iron sheet.
Uh...
Wait...
I guess...
To do that...
Honey bucket...
That's filling it up.
Honey bottle...
I guess I can just drain it?
That would be the way to do it, I think.
Also, did I actually use all my honey bottles?
I can compact it like this.
I got one of these.
Not sure if the honeycomb is something that's gonna be useful.
Uh...
To compact, we need the basin.
Basin, basin.
I think we...
What we really need is, like, one area...
Where we have the manual...
One of these operations going at all times.
So I don't have to go to the factory every time, you know?
So, for example, I would have a depot, and a basin, and all that stuff.
In fact, I'm just gonna do that now.
Like, mixing...
Mixing, right?
Is a thing.
I do need another presser, though.
Shit.
Press.
Block of iron.
I think I can do that.
It's gonna be expensive, but...
Block of iron, casing, and shaft.
Where's my casing?
There we go.
Now, we do have rotation here.
I feel like we should have this inside.
That's rotating.
These are rotating.
You can bring that over...
Nah, let's do it outside.
We can have a little thing here, maybe.
This is like the manual area.
I think I'm just gonna use the portable engine for this.
It's for a pinch, you know?
Or in a pinch.
Need some kind of gearbox...
Vertical version.
And then we're gonna have, like, a line of things.
So we're also gonna have a thing that does that.
But for now, I'm just gonna do this.
It's gonna all converge over here.
It's not gonna be super pretty.
Doesn't this come in from the back?
Yeah.
Ah, it's okay.
There we go.
Then we can fill this guy with whatever.
Coal would be the best way to do it.
Can I use this, though?
Or will it just take coal?
Oh, it works!
Sweet.
Oh, wait!
This is mixing!
Whoops.
It's not pressing.
Give me the mixer.
And bottles.
This is so funny!
So you just throw in some bottles like this?
And that?
Oh!
I see the problem.
Whoops.
That makes so much sense.
Uh, now, to figure out the best way to just...
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
God, I hate that look.
Maybe we do the other side, then?
Yeah, let's just do it like that.
It's fine.
There we go.
Now we fill it up with wood.
Spin for me!
Mix it for me!
Isn't this glass gonna break?
Okay, we got four honey bottles!
Now the question is...
If we then, uh, get rid of that...
We need a spout now.
And I do want a spout at home.
Should be easy enough to make, I think.
Dried kelp and copper...
Whoops.
Dried kelp and copper casing...
I think I used all my copper casings just now.
Uh, basically, it's pretty easy to do.
I just need copper.
And...
Was it this one?
I could just do that?
No.
It had to be wood.
Like that, and then...
There we go.
Just gonna do a couple here.
And...
And kelp.
Yeah, just one.
Nice.
This one doesn't need rotation, so...
We can just put it here, I guess.
Ah, but wait a sec!
It does need a, uh, drain.
Wait, what am I even trying to do here?
I forgot what I was actually doing.
I was making glue, that was the whole point of this.
Yeah.
So you just...
Okay, so we need honey inside here.
That's, that's the thing.
So we need honey in the drain that goes in there.
That's the way to do that.
So we need another drain.
Drain, drain, drain, drain, drain.
I, you know, I could just go back to the factory, because I have it all set up there.
But it would be nice to just have it here, you know?
Copper casing and iron bars.
Of course.
Hey, I have those!
Sick!
Whoops.
Fuck, this is too much work.
It's, it's gonna need piping and shit.
Do I even wanna...
Oh, it's still gonna need power!
You know what, fuck this.
I'm going back to the other thing.
We're doing it the old-fashioned way.
And honey...
Did I bring those?
I did not, but we can do that over here too.
That was the whole point.
I choose short-term satisfaction right now.
Sue me.
Get filled.
And then...
Uh, we're gonna...
Do this...
Oh wait, this one is not active.
Gotta turn this one off.
First connect.
Should be overstressed.
Yeah.
And then we turn these off somehow.
In here, we're gonna plop down...
Some...
Maybe five.
This one's wasted in a way.
Here we go!
Yeah!
Look at...
Oh, that was it?
There was just two?
Man, they're stingy.
We got honey glue.
But it's just gonna be the same, isn't it?
Convenient alternative to super glue.
Flicking two endpoints creates a new glued area.
Oh, it's even a different color.
That's cute.
Which can be expanded or retracted via scrolling.
Wait.
Alternatively hold alt to place an endpoint mid- Oh, I didn't even know that!
What?
That's huge!
Unlike super glue...
Honey glue does not attach to animated contraptions...
Oh!
Instead, it exclusively attaches to simul...
Oh wait, okay, good.
Good.
Good, then it works.
I guess.
I think.
Let's see.
I'm actually 50-50.
Maybe it's still gonna work, maybe it's not.
I don't know.
And all I wanted was to glue these damn things in here.
Not gonna sugarcoat it.
That's exactly what I'm doing.
Okay.
Don't think it's gonna work.
Shit!
Man.
Balls.
Could just be because I suck at gluing.
Let me try it again.
Just to confirm, you know?
So if I hold alt...
How come it's not...
How is this not covering...
Wait, that doesn't make any sense.
I started from here.
Wait, that...
That's weird.
Okay, let me start from here then.
Let me go all the way back here to there.
Yeah, it doesn't...
Yeah, okay, it's...
Yeah, you can't do multiple like...
Okay, that's weird.
Gah!
I gotta find super glue.
No, stop gluing things randomly.
Don't do it.
Well, crap.
That's a bummer.
It's honeycomb.
I feel like this could...
There's gotta be a way to...
Turn the honeycomb into normal honey.
Maybe there is a way.
Bottles.
Yeah.
On the bright side, we have a lot of food.
So when we go on expeditions...
We're gonna be mega ready this time.
So I'm still barefoot.
How about we fix that?
Some proper...
diamond...
stuff.
There we go.
And a shield would be preferable.
Now we need a bit of wood.
One more!
Put this back in there.
I'm gonna keep this wood on me.
Let's go find some slimy people.
Let's bring a bettu and all that.
Standard setup for exploration.
We got the arrows, we got the food.
I'm gonna bring my hand crank.
No.
No, I'm not gonna do that.
I could do that.
So wait, can I make like...
glue out of the belt somehow?
Like it's rubber...
Like if you heat up rubber, it's gonna become all gluey and shit.
You know?
Oh, we also need a seat on the...
on the...
on the train at some point.
But honestly, maybe it's just easier if I don't apply this to the train in front.
And I just use my normal ways of drilling in a certain direction when I encounter a mountain.
Otherwise, just built the damn track, you know what I mean?
I think that's much more preferable.
This is too janky for something that's...
it's probably not even gonna pay off.
Yeah.
That's better.
Then we also get to save these for the actual drill we're gonna use in the nether and stuff.
Much better.
Let's go on an expedition!
Where are we not gone?
Uh...
We have gone north.
South...
I feel like south may be the one direction that we have not explored that much.
Or east, actually.
So...
East is towards the spawn.
I wouldn't mind going a little southeast.
Let's go southeast.
We're going through the wooded area.
Where we used to get a lot of wood.
Also, is it getting dark or...?
Definitely is.
Time to sleep.
Information about train.
A carriage has reached the end of its track.
So I wonder if that's something that's just gonna play on its own, you know?
If I set them in motion.
Then they can transport items on their own.
I actually kinda need this.
I need it for paper.
So, where to find the green guys?
I'm thinking like in a swamp, you know?
Actually, there is a swamp towards my spawn.
We should go that way.
So it's like a little south, a little east.
Just to switch up the way back there a little.
And I'm gonna kill all the cows I see.
And sheep.
Oh, hello there.
Don't mind me.
Maybe I should set up the automatic sugar cane thingy.
Like I had in the second season.
It's not even that hard to do.
Like that's honestly one of the easier things to make.
But do I really need that much paper?
You know?
That's the question.
Now a way to automatically get honey.
Would be a pretty sick deal.
I'm really trying to keep track of where I am so I don't get lost.
In fact, I should have brought a compass.
And I gotta figure out how to reset my compass so that it points to my new home.
There's something about it in here somewhere.
Could actually be the end?
No.
Nether?
Oh, it's probably not revealed yet.
Holy cows!
I go slaughter.
Man, I was hoping...
Maybe there was something like this but in reverse.
You know?
Like we take magma cream...
And we turn it into slime ball.
Because magma cream is something you can easily farm.
Or at least easier to farm.
Now...
Keep going east.
Straight east.
I like that tree.
One single really thin tree in the distance.
Was there a pig inside that...
Sheep?
Did you see the...
The pink?
That really messed with me just now.
Maybe it was like animation of blood or something.
Uh...
Kill only these guys.
So we have more inventory.
When I find a swamp, I'm gonna kill so many of those green ones.
In fact, something I need to do...
Is...
You know the...
Things that I...
Constantly need.
Like gears...
Or cogs...
The big cogs...
The...
Gearboxes...
All that.
I need to just make...
Like hundreds of each.
Once and for all, you know?
Because there's so many times when I need them and I have to start over and make them from scratch.
Oh my god.
Sorry, I gotta go there and fix that.
And maybe also quickly say hi.
In fact, now that I'm thinking about it...
Speaking of small and big cogs...
Maybe the...
The way to do all this in the best way...
Or I'm talking efficient here...
Can't even reach it.
Is to, um...
Like start the factory, right?
But start the factory making...
The smallest...
Sort of, uh...
Components you can.
In the tree of knowledge, you know?
And then you slowly expand that factory.
The problem is you're gonna...
Pretty soon run into a bottleneck.
Such as...
Um...
Like you need infinite wood.
For that just to keep running and running and running, right?
And same with cobblestone and stuff like that.
Oh, dude.
I'm definitely stealing all this.
This...
This is gonna basically give me infinite food from my farm.
Cause I'm running really low on wheat.
Thank you.
They can make more.
They have a farm.
I'll take some apples.
Why not?
Cause apparently...
Honeydapple!
Wonder how good that is.
Maybe it's like...
Just as good as meat.
See that door is open.
That means I probably was here.
Yeah, I think I was here.
This song is on repeat.
Not seeing a swamp.
Sometimes I find the green guys in the caverns, too.
But it's kind of rare.
Weeeeaw.
There's definitely a way to create the green goo.
In a factory.
Like there has to be.
Elytra would help so much right now.
But she?
Definitely.
For a second I was like, wait...
Is there horse meat in this game?
I don't think there is.
Which is kind of weird when you think about it.
Why not?
Why isn't there horse meat?
I wanna eat horses.
I predict swamp on the other side of this mountain.
Or hill.
Based on my calculations, we should be... that's a jungle.
Kinda close?
Eh, maybe not.
You can totally feel the difference, by the way, with this meat.
Like, I've been sprinting for ages.
With no issue.
True pain would be playing Minecraft, and only having, uh, berries to heal with.
I think that would- I think that could drive anyone mad.
You know, it's- it's almost worse than waterboarding.
Just put someone in a room with Minecraft, and tell them to survive.
With only that.
Alright, grab this.
Shit's on fire, yo.
I forgot why I needed paper, but I needed it.
I just wanna see something here.
Place a train- oh, so it's actually- it does reveal more in that scenario there.
Use a mechanical press and basin to create fewer items or more.
I feel like I've done that, like, a lot.
There's also, uh, achievements for the other part of create.
Not really delved too deep into that yet.
Man, trains must be, like, the end game of create, you know, with all the stuff you need to make them.
It has been hell to get to this place.
But a good kind of hell, you know?
But man, you gotta go through a lot of hoops.
To reach this part.
And I'm talking like a proper, uh, connected railroad.
Dude, where is this swamp?
Have I not just been going east?
Like, we should be near spawn.
Oh!
That lo- wait, that's acacia.
That's not swamp.
That's, uh, well, acacia.
Acacia biome.
Not sure what you would call that.
But maybe it's an indicator of something.
Look at all this meat I'm gathering.
I need a buggy.
Something that drives off-road.
What even is that?
Like, how is this allowed to happen?
Couldn't you make a simple, if block not surrounded by anything in air, don't make?
Definitely more complicated than that, probably, but still.
Right on the other side of this hill is the swamp.
I remember.
Sorry, guys.
I need you to- I need you to die.
Okay, I'm actually lost then.
There's villages here.
Oh, I'm going so far from home, man.
How on earth are you supposed to farm this shit to make glue?
This is like the craziest, uh, bottleneck of all time.
Dude, I feel like I've overshot.
By miles.
Because usually it doesn't take this long to get home when I'm at spawn, you know?
I don't know how I did this, but I fucked it up for sure.
I'm gonna go a little north now.
I'll take some of these.
My budding jalapeno business.
Dude, if I see a portal, I'm actually just gonna go to the nether.
Oh, it's nowhere to be found!
What the hell, man?
How am I so lost?
Impossible.
Maybe over here.
There it is!
Spawn, baby!
Let's hope for some slimes.
I knew I was close.
How many beef am I at?
43!
Nice!
That's double the amount I got from my own farm.
Frogs.
Wait a minute, this is not spawn, actually.
Spawn is like a bit of a different biome.
Not sure what you would call it.
I guess I would call this one Louisiana or something.
Now where are the green guys?
Perhaps they come out at night.
Holy crap, there's a lot of animals though.
Are you stuck in the water?
There's nothing.
Don't tell me I came here for nothing.
I can't leave empty handed.
I mean, I got the meat, I guess, but...
Perhaps it is a night thing.
You gotta wait for night.
Uh...
Do you drop anything?
Okay.
I have yet to find anything from the frogs.
Yeah, they're definitely not here.
I also feel like I should be able to recognize some of this.
Did I just hear a...
Slime boy?
Oh, it's a frog!
Damn!
I got baited.
Okay, here's what we can try though.
So, I'm clearly in the swamp biome.
Let's try and dig down and see if we find a cave.
Because technically, if we find a cave, we should still be in the swamp biome.
And, uh, maybe down there, there's a lot of slimes.
That's my theory.
I just wanna find a good spot where we're definitely in the center of the biome, like over here.
I would say maybe...
Well, it's kinda like this is on the edge of something, so maybe over there is better.
I don't wanna accidentally wander off away from the biome down there.
I don't know why the color of the grass is changing like this.
But I mean, I guess, I guess this is, this would be it, right?
Let's just dig.
Fuck it.
We're not going straight down.
I learned that lesson.
Many times, in fact.
Oh, wait, I should've brought my, um, Silk Touch pickaxe.
Because it will produce more items from diamonds and stuff.
Now that we know how the crushing wheel works.
I hear a cave.
Nope, that's water.
That's also water.
Damn.
Maybe we make a little turn here.
That's also water.
Damn it!
Keep going, I believe.
Just keep blocking the water.
Circumvent it.
Here's a cave.
Oh, by the way!
There is one thing we have not found yet, by the way.
And that is...
Uh...
You know, the Shulker...
No, the Skulk!
Skulk areas!
We should really start looking for those.
Usually they're inside caves on the mountains.
Maybe some of the items in there will, um, unlock new things and create, you know?
I feel like this is a dead end down here.
But I'm gonna keep going a little longer.
More water.
Gosh dang it!
Nothing I hate more than water when I'm digging.
That has to be, like, one of the top bad things in Minecraft.
Uh, shovel...
Not even hearing any animals.
Okay, now we're getting deep.
And...
They're not gonna be down here, are they?
Let's try and go back up.
It's probably night now.
Maybe that will do something.
Maybe the slimy guys are here.
If they're not, then I honestly am at a loss.
No clue where to find them.
Or how to consistently get a hold of the green stuff.
It's night.
Anything?
Come on.
Look at this skeleton.
Filt with fungi.
I feel like that's a rare one.
Dude, there's nothing here.
That feels bad.
Did you see that jump?
That was a massive jump!
10 out of 10.
I mean, there's all kinds of monsters, just not the one I need.
My theory was that, okay, if they do indeed spawn in the caves in this biome, it's because it's dark down there, right?
And if it's night out here, maybe they also spawn on the surface.
Because it's night.
But there's nothing.
We're gonna have to go back to the drawing board on this and find a different way to get this green goop.
I'm out of here.
Being chased by a wolf, you love to see it.
And who knows, maybe on the way back we find the actual swamp that I was spawned in.
Like, I could have sworn I had seen green goop guys in the swamp, you know, at some point.
Kind of an interesting set of biomes here.
I think the next big thing we need to do is to go find Elytra.
That is, like, the huge thing right now.
Especially now that we have a way to get gunpowder very easily.
This will make things insanely efficient.
I also miss being able to fly around.
Wait, maybe if I collect stuff like this...
Like...
Maybe I can somehow make the green balls...
Okay, that doesn't work.
But maybe this stuff?
I think I need the gardening hose.
Don't have that right now.
Oh, it was a frog.
You know what?
I have a feeling.
Let me try one more dig.
Uno mas!
Let me also see here...
Yeah, yeah, actually, yes.
Let's try this one more time.
If we can find a cave.
Oh, damn.
Well, that's no good.
Let's try the other direction.
This way.
And then we can maybe turn right.
Here.
I hear something.
Isn't that the sound of a green guy?
Make a sound.
I went too deep?
Okay, whatever.
Maybe I'm imagining things.
Oh, I actually do need coal.
Get rid of...
Trust there's a cave down here, and there's gonna be green guys.
Ah!
Why you gotta do this to me?
I hate it.
Fine.
I'll leave.
In fact, now that I think about it.
Is the green guy the most rare creature in Minecraft?
Oh, it was the frog making that sound anyway.
It wasn't even the guy.
I think it may be one of the rarest creatures you can find.
I'm gonna stay with night.
I'm not gonna sleep.
Just in case I find something.
Hey, another swamp!
Okay, well, I think we can pretty much confirm at this point.
That the green guys are not in the swamp.
Because I feel like we would have seen one by now.
We've been here day, we've been here night, we've been in multiple swamps.
They're not here.
I think it's the other swamp biome.
So not Louisiana.
That's crazy.
Could've sworn it was here.
There's jungle though.
Maybe I'll take some cocoa with me.
If I'm out here exploring anyway, I want souvenirs, dammit.
Souvenirs from far away lands.
Maybe some bamboo as well.
Just a bit.
One stack.
I see cocoa!
Wait, this is the other type of swamp!
Mangrove!
Maybe that's what it's called, actually.
And this is mud, I guess?
Maybe there's something we can do with mud.
Oh shit.
I'm running out of space.
These guys.
I think I may need to use the gardening hose on them.
Come on, green guys.
Show up, man.
Make my day.
I think this is the spot.
But it could be at night.
In fact, something I've noticed.
I feel like in these biomes, enemies don't spawn.
And I mean like skeletons and stuff.
It's like they just don't appear in these.
I could just be imagining that, but...
I just don't ever remember seeing an enemy in here.
Yeah, look, it's completely empty.
It's almost eerie, actually.
Going back.
I think we're gonna go to the end.
We're gonna find a city.
We're gonna get a Lutra, and we're gonna change our stars.
Being able to fly all over the land is gonna make it much easier to spot potential green guys.
We're gonna dive down on them like a talon thingy.
Like a...
I was thinking of grey talon from Deadlock.
But you know, the bird that goes like...
And then down.
Bald eagle.
From America.
I've always wanted to hear that screech in real life, you know?
The classic American screech.
Never heard that.
Never seen one of those things.
Dude, more than one stack of beef.
We're eating good tonight.
Our trip to the end is gonna be so much more comfortable with good food.
Last time all I had was those teleporter fruits.
And it was horrible.
I do not recommend.
That was just to clean it up.
I also don't want that mud.
See, this spot I recognized.
Danish cows over there.
We're close to home.
We got the ship there.
Yep, yep, yep.
Now I'm trying to think.
Maybe the slime balls...
Can also be found in chests somewhere.
I was thinking maybe we should go for...
Or find pirate chests or something.
Or treasure chests.
But I don't think they actually are in there.
Trying to think of all the ways we can get it.
There's gotta be a way to craft them.
We gotta figure it out.
If we can craft them, that would solve all our problems.
Right?
Slime...
Lock.
Hey, we can ponder the slime ball?!
That's kinda crazy.
Disconnected sections of simulated contraptions will split off.
Okay.
Oh!
I wonder why it's the slime ball for this and not just the superglue.
Maybe because you don't select an area and it's more like from one block to another and then it's...
Yeah, I guess that's why.
I guess we gotta find everything that's green and see if that somehow creates...
But we need a garden hose.
Like, I'm thinking if we get stuff from the ocean, you know, maybe that will allow us to craft...
A slime ball.
Hmm...
I'm gonna leave it.
Disgusting.
Cheers.
Man, I can't believe there's still ice in my ice tea.
Like, it's been in here for...
Hours.
But the thing is, it now tastes only of water.
Because most of the ice is melted.
I feel like I should take that down as well at some point, just destroy it completely.
Or...
We make it into a simulated contraption and push it into the ocean.
Hahahaha!
Let it fall to the bottom of the ocean?
Hey, that's actually not a bad idea.
Maybe that is one way to...
Chop down a mountain.
If you think about it.
Or you simulate like, a whole area of a mountain and then you drag it away.
And you let it all fall into a crushing wheel.
Not sure if a simulated contraption will be able to fall into a crushing wheel, but...
Maybe.
Okay, so we should be home in a second here.
Okay, so here's the plan.
I'm gonna go through some recipes, we're gonna see if we can't find a way to craft this damn slime ball.
And we're not just gonna check the crafting table, we're gonna check the furnace crafting list and all the other, you know, specialized stations.
Because those are the ones I usually miss.
So for example, here.
You know?
Or maybe the smoker...
No, there's nothing in there.
Okay, nevermind.
So I checked it all, there's nothing.
Great.
What about this one?
Slime.
There's nothing.
Yeah, we need this.
Mechanical arm.
There's gotta be a way to reverse this.
Like, if I can take this and somehow...
Maybe wash it, or...
Navigation table.
Oh, yeah.
That's huge.
Let's go feed some animals.
I'm gonna turn all of these into that.
No, actually...
Oh, okay, it's fine.
Eating time.
I already have so much food, but this is just for the future.
It's a good habit.
Everyone gets fed.
Yep, yep, yep.
Also you guys.
And you...
You...
Beautiful.
I think I got them all.
Now the cocoa beans.
Let me see that.
Cocoa...
Choc...
Chocolate glazed berries.
Makes sense.
So you can also make chocolate...
Glazed...
Different things.
So a bar of chocolate, for example.
Choc...
Bar of chocolate.
Yeah, you just put it in there.
I guess we gotta fill it up with...
A bottle first.
And then put it in the drain.
Makes sense.
And...
Blaze cake base.
I have a feeling the crushing wheel is somehow gonna be instrumental in making...
The green goop, you know?
Maybe some of the outputs here...
It's gonna do something.
Diorite makes nether quartz.
That...
That is...
Not expected at all.
Like...
Okay, clay ball.
Hold on.
Clay ball.
Surely that can be used somehow.
Clay?
We get clay from dripstone.
Oh, that makes sense actually.
I don't think I've tried to just make clay.
Okay, so we can make colored clay, I guess?
It's the furnace recipe.
Oh, it's terracotta!
Ah!
Well, there you go.
Now we have a bunch of coal we can use.
That's wonderful.
Paper in there and clay balls.
No, actually these go here.
Raw copper.
Fuck me!
I can't believe I didn't find a single green guy on that expedition.
It's actually so infuriating.
Like, I literally can't do anything.
Unless I find this dude, you know?
Shit!
Cocoa beans.
That's food.
I do want to try and make a honeyed apple.
But I ran out of honey.
Actually, didn't we have a honey home here somewhere?
Did I cut it down?
Oh wait, did I actually move that?
Why did I do that?
What's wrong with me?
I had it all set up here perfectly.
I'll need a silk touch pickaxe to pick up that campfire.
And you know what?
I'm going to carry around this thing.
So we can start collecting green stuff.
In the hopes that we can create the green bowl.
Wow, that takes a while.
Did he pick it up?
He stole my campfire!
Bastard!
That's so rude.
In fact, we need a bit of light here.
If he can move all the way up there, that's not a good sign.
Perimeter expanded.
I could use my haunted bell.
But it's not really that useful.
Okay, I think we're going to go to the end now.
We're going to have a shit ton of stakes.
We got everything we need.
I guess, ideally, we want to make the train track go to the end.
You know, we're going to make it go across water on bridges and stuff.
And then when we reach the area over the end stronghold, we're going to create like a train station there.
With not an elevator, but something that easily takes me up and down, you know?
It's going to be connected.
All the important places like that need to be connected with railway.
That's the goal.
Let me grab my stakes.
Stakes, stakes, stakes, stakes.
And, man, I have so much meat!
I'm so not used to that.
We don't need lobbies, so let's see where we're going.
More torches for sure, so I'm going to grab some of these.
From here.
Sticks I got.
We don't want to get lost in the end, right?
So the idea is to go there.
We're going to find elytra.
Do I need the mutton?
I don't think I do.
So we actually need paper for this.
Good thing I just got it, huh?
We need paper, and...
Do I even have...
I do have gunpowder.
Nice.
We're going to make this.
I'm going to bring both stacks.
No.
What if I die?
Leave one stack at home.
And we're going to put this in here.
We can put this back here.
Now, gunpowder?
That was a way to make it.
Oh, yes!
Cinderflower, dude!
But Potion of Harming, I don't know how to make that one.
That's a little bit of a mystery still.
Wait, this makes three?
Is that more than the way I do it manually?
No, it's the same.
Okay.
Wouldn't surprise me though, you know?
Campfire, we don't really need that right now.
That's equipment.
Bucket we have.
Glass bottles, we don't need that either.
For the end.
Silk touch?
Do I need that for the end?
Maybe some things I do want to...
Mmm...
No.
I actually don't think I need it.
I'm going to save as much space as I can here.
Leave it there.
I don't think I need...
Yes, I'm going to bring this because I'm going to go underwater a little bit.
The bed is going to be useless to me.
But it's good to have before we go into the end.
I was thinking maybe we bring some pearls.
Ah, wait a minute.
Did I die in the end?
I remember collecting a shit ton of pearls.
Where did they go?
Ah, here they are!
Nice!
Very good, man.
I got them.
We can use this to teleport across...
areas.
I'm also going to bring a bunch of...
blocks...
No, I don't have any.
Okay, that's fine.
Ah, that's cool.
I'm going to grab the end stone blocks in there and use them to make bridges.
That's the deal right now.
Now, other than that...
We got the armor, we got the shield.
It's fully repaired.
Pickaxe.
We even have a bow.
Not that it's super useful against Endermen.
But it is useful against the little creatures.
I think I'm ready.
In fact, I don't need this many pearls.
I think 16 is fine.
Let's head off.
Go to sleep first.
Operation Find Elytra so we can find Green Goop.
That's begun.
Uh, wrong way.
The initial search for the Green Goop was unsuccessful.
We checked multiple swamps at day and night.
Nothing.
Now we're going to brute force this shit.
Now, obviously, we gotta find a, um...
We're gonna find the wings first.
Otherwise, it's not gonna...
Oh, and by the way, it's not gonna have a lot of durability either at first.
So we will have to put Mending on it.
And that's not something I have.
So maybe the idea is to also kidnap some villagers at some point.
Turn them into magicians.
And have them enchant my stuff.
That's something I haven't even thought about yet.
But I think what I wanna do in that case is...
I wanna connect...
Connect my, uh...
Railroad.
Or my train tracks.
To a nearby village.
And then have that village be the place where I can buy things.
It'll be like going into town, right?
I don't wanna bring the town to my place cause it was kind of annoying in the...
In the last world I had where I had villagers all over my shit, you know?
I am a hermit.
So I'm gonna live like a hermit.
And then when I wanna buy things, I go into town.
Just like real life.
Gonna be good.
That's the plan.
It makes me happy.
Now I remember the path here.
There should be some water in a second.
And then a smooth sailing.
I maybe have to trap the villagers though in the village, you know?
So they don't wander off.
Like I'll put them in their little respective houses.
So I know where to go.
I'll even put a big sign on them that says, I sell mending.
That's my purpose.
I hope I haven't forgotten anything, man.
I'm really trying to avoid the situation of going into the end, and then realizing immediately that I fucked up.
But I feel like I double checked everything, I should be good.
Potion of harming.
I am going to assume that...
Potion of harming...
Is made with something that is create related.
You know?
But I assume also it's gonna be an awkward potion.
At first.
And...
I'm trying to think what is like specifically create that could make sense in a potion.
I guess like endstone powder, actually.
Or obsidian powder.
Some of those.
Because powders are the thing that go into potions in Minecraft, right?
Or at least a lot of the time they make sense there.
Dude, we're gonna totally experiment with the potions of...
The new powders.
Then again, powders usually have some sort of effect on an already existing potion.
Such as making it last longer, like redstone powder.
Or...
Making it more effective.
Stuff like that.
Okay, so we should...
It should be right...
There where my cursor is.
Let's see how precise I am today.
Oh!
Last time I was on the right!
That was close.
Hey!
Is that creative music?
I don't recognize this.
Whatever it is, it's nice.
Another boat to the collection here.
In fact, I'm gonna bring it with me.
Uh...
Where is the entrance?
Actually, let's get some air first.
And...
Go!
Adventure awaits.
Please don't change the music!
You bastard game!
Keep it rolling, man!
Dang it.
Where's the...
Entrance to the thingy?
Somewhere here.
Ah!
Look at that beautiful staircase.
That is actually super beautiful.
I dig that.
Okay, wish me luck here.
Let's see if I can hit it.
No, actually, if I overshoot...
That...
Man, that would kill me if I did...
Like, I would hate...
That would be the worst.
I still get nervous doing it, you know?
Okay, so I went that way last time.
I'm gonna go that same way again.
There's no other good ways, it seems.
Let's hit...
In here...
Are these guys gonna push me off the edge?
Sir!
Oh my god!
I don't like that at all.
That's scary.
Okay, so I think I'm gonna go either...
You know, I could also just keep it simple here.
And just go in one direction.
SLJ in the end?
Is that too cheeky for ya?
Well, approximately SLJ.
I don't even doubt that I'm gonna find Elytra, by the way.
I'm gonna find...
Like, I'm thinking, how many should I bring home?
You know?
I'm not thinking, oh, am I gonna bring one home?
No, of course I am.
The machine gun...
Oh no!
It's a massive gulsh!
Duh!
Okay, let's go this way then.
No, it's also massive!
Guess I'm making a bridge.
But I mean, this bridge will serve generations, you know?
In fact, maybe I'll even bring the train in here.
Hmm?
Because apparently you can put a train through a portal or something.
That is actually kind of...
Interesting, isn't it?
I wanna see how that works.
Okay, that should do it for now.
Oh!
I'm gonna go to this island.
Find the optimal angle here.
That's a good angle.
I don't think I've ever slipped doing this and fell down, you know?
That has never occurred.
I wonder when the first time is gonna be.
Like, at some point it'll happen, right?
Alright, almost there.
I may actually use a pearl at the end here.
Oh my god.
Oh my god!
Holy shit, man, that is...
Let's keep going.
Hmm...
This way.
I need to keep placing these.
I cannot get lost in there.
There we go!
We find something!
But do we have Elytra?
It doesn't look like it!
Shit.
I'm still gonna rob the place, though.
Because last time I didn't get enough.
Love the pearls!
Boy, am I glad I brought all this food.
Dude.
Really glad.
Dude, I'm actually so good with the pearls.
Look around, see if I can see other potential targets.
Nothing.
I'm gonna pearl the shit out of this, too.
Ha!
Oh, not even close!
Okay, I was doubting.
Fuckin' hell.
Whoa!
Fuck you!
I forgot your voice lines.
You suck.
Don't hit me.
Teleporter.
Get outta here.
Where's my bow at?
Oh, there you are.
Open up!
Let me see your mouth.
Come on!
Oh, no.
Okay, actually, it's fine, it's fine.
Suck on that.
Ow!
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow!
I need this to be there.
Ow!
Oh my god, this is actually annoying!
Let me in!
Okay, guess we're ascending.
Wait, how come I can't see the timer on the...
debuff?
Usually I can see timers.
Wait, there's not gonna be anything here, man.
I'm gonna keep walking around.
I'm wasting resources on these fools.
So, I came from...
I believe over here.
No.
Shit.
Where did I come from?
Okay, look for...
torches.
Must be over here.
You know what, it's fine.
I don't need to know where I am.
We just need to find another portal to get home.
Look, there's one.
Easy peasy, lemon squeezy.
We're going that way.
Believe.
It's pearl time!
Uh...
We're gonna pearl...
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Am I dead?
Oh my god, I don't like this!
What the fuck?
Oh...
I'm lost.
I don't know where I am.
I need stone.
Dude, I feel...
I thought I was dead.
When I missed the ledge.
My heart sank.
I thought I was good with the pearl.
I wasn't.
Greatly overestimated my strength there.
Okay, we're gonna bridge like a normal person.
No more heroics.
Let's do it.
Hoi!
Oh my god, my fingers are weirdly placed.
You know how when you start thinking about when you're breathing, and then you start to manual breathe?
I'm manual holding the button right now, which is super weird.
Like, normally I don't have a problem holding the button, you know?
But now that I'm aware of it, it makes it weirder.
Keep going.
Wait, I feel like I should bring more food.
Like, this is not enough food.
I should have brought even more.
I see something!
That could be it.
Let's check it out.
Perhaps...
Big tower?
Looks like a possibility.
Yeah!
Nice!
There's a ship in the air!
If you can even call this air.
There's probably empty space in the air.
I'm...
tempting...
I'm resisting...
the temptation...
of pearling.
Come on!
You better not let go of that button, you bastard.
Straight line.
SLJ.
Oh my god!
I'm so scared of falling!
I keep thinking that it hasn't happened before, you know?
And that it's gonna happen soon.
Which is making me, like...
play weird.
Oh god, oh god, oh god, oh god.
No more bridging, please.
In fact, I'm just gonna...
purl my ass up into that ship.
Try to think what else I can collect in here.
To bring back home a souvenir.
Nooo!
There's a massive...
gap!
Fuck.
Ooh!
Okay.
Watch this.
I will have the exact amount of blocks I need to cross.
What are the chances I have exactly the amount?
You'll see.
This is one of my skills in life.
Like, it's a useless skill, but I have it, you know?
I can tell...
exactly how many I need.
Watch.
I have the exact amount I need.
Hup!
I told you!
Exact amount.
Beautiful.
Now, where's the ship?
Oh, it's right there.
Oh my god!
I'm a...
I'm a professional.
Oh, that was beautiful!
What's up, nerd?
Give me the treasure I came here for.
We got it!
We are so back in business.
Ooh, look at all...
Oh my god!
Mending on this!
Whoa!
And we actually need iron, too.
This is fantastic loot!
What?!
That's like crazy loot!
Bane of Arthropods, too!
Holy crap!
Wow!
Well, guys, we're going flying.
Oh!
Sweet!
Potion of healing?
Why not?
I'll take this.
Yep, yep, yep.
And...
Oh!
I looked at one!
I think.
No, we're fine.
Oh, you want to die?
Are you an Arthropod?
No, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Give me that.
Uh, now to remember how to use the Elytra.
Um...
You basically just jump and use rockets, right?
It's just that simple.
Wait, where did I come from?
Must have come from back there, I think.
Look for bridges.
Bro, where are the bridges at?
Oh, there it is.
So that means we're gonna...
Yeah!
We are back, dude!
Oh, this is nice.
We gotta watch the durability.
Oh my god, it's so much easier to traverse.
It's...
It's almost like it was made for this area.
I wanna find another one, another Elytra.
I'm just gonna go in one direction here.
Uh, maybe it's over here?
I have a sense, I have a feeling.
Okay, it's losing durability somewhat fast.
Which is not pleasing me.
Wait, we're kind of approaching...
Dead...
Space?
What?
Is that the edge?
The hell?
Look at this!
Oh, there's something!
Aww...
It's nothing.
It's a tiny one.
No ship for me.
Wait, is this...
Dude, I'm home!
Somehow I made it home.
That's insane.
Let's go the other direction, then.
I still have some durability.
Let's check this way out.
I'm gonna go somewhat straight, so we know which way to go if we go home.
Oh, we can't be turning too much blade speed.
Here we go!
Looks like a dead one.
Oh, we got more over here.
I mean, those are big ones?
That could be nice loot in there.
We should investigate.
Let's check out this one first.
Oh my god, we're so fucking back.
I need my bow.
Bow, bow, bow, bow, bow.
Fuck!
Let me down!
Wait, I can just float.
So as soon as it releases, I should just press...
Wait, do I press it once?
That's the thing I'm not sure about.
Oh my god, they're so annoying!
Okay, get ready to...
I don't know.
Maybe I press it once.
I don't have enough time to...
Oh my god.
How do you even counter this?
Okay, once.
You press once.
Great.
You know what?
Just get down here so we don't fly away.
Oh my god.
They are so infuriating!
Got one.
Another one.
Nice.
Suck on that!
Where are you?
Are you on the outside?
You better be.
Okay, that's boring.
That's kinda cool.
But they're...
They're shovels!
I mean, they're iron.
Don't really want iron.
Hey, but we can disenchant it.
Right, we can put them in here.
This is disenchanting purposes.
Wait, they stack too?!
Is that the exact same enchant then?
Wait, how does that work?!
Weird!
Look at the way they stack!
That's blowing my mind.
Diamonds.
Okay, we have robbed this place successfully.
Move on.
We're gonna go to the top floor.
Oh my god, so efficient.
What's up bros?
Oh wait, there's not even loot in here?
What a scam!
Do I even want to kill you?
I don't know.
Definitely loot up here.
Yeah, come on, come on.
Yes!
Sup guys!
I've come to steal your shit- Oh shit.
Oh no.
Ah, annoying.
I got hit.
I'm hit!
Just get down here, get down here.
Honestly, just rob them and get out.
Wait, what?
I thought this was the same chest we just had.
Confused me.
Oh.
Thank you.
Thank you!
See you later.
See ya.
Good talk.
Hot soup.
What about this one?
That's probably empty.
There's a guy in there.
That one was empty.
What do we have back here?
This one could be a good one.
Let's check it out.
Honestly, I don't feel good.
I don't feel good.
Take me home!
Ah!
Get me out, get me out, get me out, get me out!
Ow, ow, ow, ow.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Calm down.
We're going home.
Sort of.
Yeah.
I don't want to waste all my durability on this Elytra.
We're... yeah.
We're going home.
We got some good loot.
We got what we came for.
Everything's dandy.
Now, the portal should be over here somewhere.
There it is.
I think I may have just angered an Enderman.
Not 100% sure.
Let's see if I can land on this.
Ah!
Close!
Nice!
Oh!
What?!
I thought I was floating!
Imagine I died there.
Now tell me I slept at home.
I better appear right in my home in my bed.
With a hot cup of chocolate in my hand.
And a bag of snacks.
Go!
Yes!
No chocolate though.
Beautiful!
We have made it home successfully with the Lutra!
Man, that was so nice.
And we got some really good loot out of it too.
I mean, look at all these goodies.
You know what I'm thinking, partner?
Enchantment!
Or disenchantment, technically.
Purse of Binding?
Hmmmm... Oh wait, that's the one that makes it so that I can't take it off, I think.
So I don't want to put that on.
I'm gonna disenchant it.
Am I though?
Hmmmm... No.
Let's not do that.
This one I'll disenchant.
Okay, this one... I don't think I'm gonna disenchant that, actually.
It's kinda good.
Holy... Dude!
This is a sick pickaxe!
Yo, we merged these two, we're gonna have a god pickaxe!
Wow!
Didn't even see the haul I just got!
Crazy!
Man!
What else did I get?
Fortune 2, efficiency 4?
That means we can probably do efficiency 5.
Oh wait, these become efficiency 5.
These two are we gonna disenchant.
And that one.
Dude, we should go to the end more!
This is, like, incredible!
Efficiency 5 in mending, though.
Like...
That's kind of crazy!
But, uh...
I'd rather have the experience.
Who needs iron?
Not me!
And now we're level 30!
Oh, nice!
Let's throw away some stuff here.
I think I should make a bow next.
Like, cause I miss my good bow, you know?
The one I lost in the Great Disaster of 26.
And the reason I couldn't make, uh...
A new one was because I didn't have string last time.
But now I do.
Yeah.
My inventory is crap, of course.
Potions?
We can put them in here.
Okay!
Oh!
Right, make the bow.
Let's see what we got.
Please, give me...
Uh...
Power.
Flame...
I mean, we can take a chance, I guess.
Or...
Let's check a pick...
Pickaxe.
See if there's a silk touch.
Because we do...
Kinda love silk touch now.
Ever since the...
Wheel discovery.
Okay, efficiency.
So that's not good.
I think we should take the chance on flame.
There's a chance we get...
Insane power at the same time.
And I've gotten pretty lucky today.
Hell yeah!
We're gonna merge this with that!
Holy crap!
Now that we're level 27, we can start doing fancy things in here.
First off...
Oh!
23?
Okay, that's...
That's more like it.
Fortune 3.
Efficiency 5.
Unbreaking 3.
And Mending!
Oh boy!
That is...
Fantastic.
Unbelievable.
Next up, we're gonna take this one and that one.
Power 4...
Actually...
No, yeah, this is...
This is definitely good.
That's a fantastic bow now!
Then we have these guys.
Don't think we need to do anything with those.
We are slowly peeking again!
But we can't put all our peeks in one basket, meaning if I end up dying somewhere stupid again...
That...
That we don't lose everything, you know?
This is the lesson I have learned.
That shall not happen ever again.
Hey, we can merge these two as well.
That's gonna make a pretty good shovel.
Oh, crap!
Oh, okay, I can definitely get one level though.
I must have cooked something.
There we go, level 8.
Beautiful.
That's a good shovel.
We got mending on two of my items now.
That's fantastic.
And...
We didn't have...
We didn't have it on this, but I'm not gonna put that on, because then I can't take it off.
In fact, hold on.
Isn't that kind of...
Really bad?
Imagine you...
You get this.
Can you ever take it off then?
Because it has mending.
It will always heal.
Are you forever stuck with this?
Dude, that scares me so much, we're gonna have to disenchant that immediately.
Fuck that crap.
That's like poison.
That's a poison pill.
You don't wanna eat it.
Take this.
Diamonds.
Time to sword.
Shulker shells!
There was something we could make with that.
This one.
A chest.
Chest, chest, chest.
Maybe that will unlock something new.
And create.
No?
Okay.
But it's nice to have, I guess.
I mean, look at all this space.
It's basically like...
I would say it's equivalent to the toolbox.
In terms of usefulness.
The toolbox is smaller.
But it does hold way more of one specific type of block, right?
This one is more like random shit.
Go.
So it's good to have with us.
We can even color it.
Let's make a different color.
Maybe we can make it...
Do I even have any colors?
There's...
Black dye!
Make it black.
I like it.
Wait, can I not?
It has to be possible.
Yeah!
Well, there it is.
How come it didn't show in my recipes?
Weird.
Dude, this is gonna make me think I have blackstone.
It's actually a bad idea.
Get another color.
That's bad.
Dice.
Give me dice.
We can make a blue one.
Or we can make a lime one.
I kinda like brown to, you know, match with my toolbox.
So, cocoa.
Coco.
What did I just...
What did I just say?!
Oh, yeah.
Round dye.
Question is though, can I just keep doing this?
Yes, I can!
Wonderful!
Now you go in there.
All these I don't need.
We bring the diamond hoe with us.
And maybe I'll start...
Using my...
Axe?
No, my...
Do I have a better axe, actually?
No.
Okay.
No, you know what?
I...
My axe is good for combat.
The axe is the definitive combat weapon.
Bum, bum!
We don't need blue dye.
In fact, I should probably just make a bunch of dyes as well.
Have a dye chest.
Ingots.
These pearls can go back in...
Here...
No, here.
Actually, they belong in there.
Don't need that many torches.
Bed is nice.
So the brewing stand...
That's construction.
Rest is looking...
Fantastic!
I think we are ready to...
Perform a miracle.
And that miracle is gonna be...
Exploration!
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Let me make a...
Compass first.
Compass!
There we go.
Never getting lost again.
Now, maybe we should figure out the thing with, um...
It was lodestone!
Wasn't it?
But I forgot how to make it.
Fuck.
Whatever.
I'm gonna go explore.
Oh, leave the...
Stuff behind here.
Let's go find the green dudes.
Now that we have the...
Elytra.
Are you ready?
We are...
I'm going west now.
And we're gonna stick to one direction.
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Hold on.
We...
We can't.
I forgot about durability.
Fuck me.
We can't do it.
I almost made a...
Crucial mistake.
We...
We gotta...
We gotta shelve the Elytra for now.
Wait a minute.
Wait.
We can repair it though.
Uh...
We can repair it with...
Whatchamacallit.
The flappy wings.
I don't have it.
Uh...
Do I have a book of mending?
I don't.
Hmm.
Damn it.
We can't use it yet.
We gotta shelve it.
In fact, we should make a little item.
Item display thingy.
And we need sticks for that.
If I am not mistaken...
Does memory serve right?
Item...
Oh my god, I'm amazing.
Huh?
We unlocked something wholly new!
Oh, I guess because we got color suddenly a bunch of stuff happened.
Placard.
Frame your items in brass using this fancy wall panel.
Save for contraptions.
When right clicked with item, adds the held item to the placard.
Emits a brief redstone signal if a matching item was present already.
Really?
Let's make it.
That sounds fun.
Oh, I have it.
Yeah!
Actually, that looks amazing.
Very nice display.
Okay, I think we're ready.
I'm just gonna go normally.
Ah man, do I really wanna go look for the green guys again?
I'm losing my mind about that.
Fuck that noise.
There's gotta be a way to...
Oh, hold on.
Let's think about this logically.
Green goop.
Let's make everything that has...
What's that?
Oh!
Potato Cannon!
Needs the precision mechanism!
Okay.
I mean...
Launches your homegrown vegetables at enemies.
Oh, wait, is this actually good?
How good is this?
I'll have to try that.
Anyway, what I was about to say...
Let's just make everything that is green.
Wait, Wand of Symmetry.
Mirrors block placement while present in any...
Hotbar slot.
Wait, mirrors...
Mirrors block placement?
When used on a surface.
Creates or moves its mirror?
What?
Oh!
So you create sort of a...
Let's say you specify a block or...
An axis.
And then whatever blocks you place on one side...
Is gonna be placed on the other, maybe?
That's what I'm getting from that.
You know?
Let's make a...
Hey, we...
Yeah, everything green...
Let's make green stuff.
Uh...
Didn't I bring home bamboo?
Bam...
Oh, it's...
Oh!
Let's look at the green chest!
Of all things, huh?
Mmm...
Block.
Oh!
What is that?
That's probably not related.
Duh!
Slime!
Do I have enough to make that?
Oh, I'm rich, actually.
Where's Stuart when you need him?
Uh...
Block...
Oh, right, we can turn them back, I guess.
Okay, cool.
Well, we're unlocking things, so that's good.
Uh, let me just look through everything.
Like, I wanna combine this search with also just making new stuff.
Like this one.
But we need a crushing wheel, which is a whole endeavor in itself right now, because I took down the mechanical crafters.
So that'll come soon.
Fate Mark.
Minecart coupling...
I kinda wanna try and make the full cardboard set.
I gotta be honest, like, the whole stealth thing sounds amazing.
To make cardboard...
Pulp.
And pulp was water and green, right?
Yeah.
Wait, maybe you need to make pulp to make, uh...
The green...
Maybe that's part of the process.
Ah, but I would've unlocked that, I guess, at this point.
Bam.
Okay, so, water.
Um...
Water, water, water.
I think we may need to set up a little system again.
With, like, a little pool of water that's being pulled in.
To do this.
Man.
Okay, it's not that hard.
We just need stuff like that.
No, what was it?
No, pulp was the mixing thing.
Hey, we have a mixing setup, actually!
Let's just grab some water.
It's not that bad.
Okay, dude.
Leave me alone.
Find someone else to harass.
Uh, actually, I should make a little pool here.
That I can keep grabbing.
Let's grab a bunch of greens.
No, we can use the bamboo.
Okay, you wanna die?
No, go sleep.
Oh, I think I'm gonna need some coal here.
Give me all.
Actually, I'm gonna do something crazy.
It's not that crazy, but I'm gonna put in one at a time.
Because I think it's wasting away when I'm not using it.
Okay, well, that was one pulp.
Let's, uh...
Add way more.
Let's let it run!
Let her rip!
As soon as it runs out, I supply it with one more.
Oh, ran out of- Ran out of water there.
Okay.
I'm gonna grab a couple more buckets.
Even though I think we only need three.
I'm gonna have a little infinite water situation here.
Oh my god, that's digging fast.
I'm not used to this.
The enchantments...
Are out of control!
Is this kinda scuffed?
I know.
But it's okay.
That's doing its thing.
Actually, I'm gonna put two more in here.
Mega pulp.
I have more greens.
Oh wait, bamboo planks!
Anything- Oh, that looked new.
Is that a bamboo window?
It's a little scuffed, but it's okay.
We're making lots of cardboard now.
I guess maybe a water wheel would be ideal.
For something like this.
Keep mixing.
Let's see how many I have.
24!
Sweet.
Cardboard time.
Oh.
Is it...
Over here?
Ah, we press it now!
We can definitely set that up.
I even made a press for this exact purpose.
I wonder if there's an easy way to transform this into that motion, like, fast.
There's gotta be a block that does that.
Cause it's a little cumbersome.
Uh...
That's gotta be a thing.
Let's see here.
It's gotta be like a normally-shaped block.
Oh, it- I guess it would be this.
Except that's going in the other way.
Splay board.
Hmm.
I mean, okay, fine.
It's okay.
Do it the old-fashioned way.
The question is, what is the old- Oh, I probably need some gear.
Boxes.
Where are you?
I may not have them.
Um...
Remember what I said earlier?
We should make a shit ton of everything?
We're gonna do that now.
Except we don't have alloys.
So we can't do that right now.
Piss!
But Andeside, perhaps, could be the savior.
If I have it.
I don't see it.
Maybe up here?
Oh, oh, oh, oh!
It wasn't there!
Incredible.
That was a shot in the dark.
And it hit beautifully.
Now we need the little nuggets.
We can turn these into nuggets.
Fill this up.
Okay, now what?
Now that we have all this, we can make a bunch of shafts.
Let's make two stacks of shafts.
Three stacks of shafts.
Never gonna run out again.
And now we need wood to make gears.
And I have a bunch of wood too.
This inventory is way too small.
Cog.
Oh, right.
Turn them into normal planks.
Full stack of cogs, baby!
We need more.
Now we make the big ones.
Wait, no, no, no, no, no.
Uh, cog.
That one.
Tell me that isn't beautiful.
And then with all of this, we're gonna make gearboxes.
Seventeen gearboxes.
And half of those are gonna be vertical gearboxes.
Why am I running out?
Is it because I don't have enough wood?
Oh, is it my...
These ones.
I need more.
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
What?
Oh, the... OH!
Oh shit, those take a lot.
I see.
Forgot about that.
So, shafts we have.
Now we need wood.
Okay, okay.
No problem.
Another full stack gearboxes this time.
Sixteen more.
Now we go even crazy with this.
And we're not done!
We're not done!
We make shafts now again because we ran out shafts.
Shit ton of shafts!
We're not done.
More cocks.
Okay, we're done.
That's it, baby.
We are now ready for anything forever and always.
At least for the next 200 years.
Isn't that beautiful?
Never shall we cry about this again.
Oh yeah, the reason I made this is because I needed it.
Right.
Instead of taking one, how about you take a stack, huh?
Wait, did I... where are my cocks?
Did I... cocks?
Big stack of... 33.
Don't need the big ones.
I guess I must have used them all.
We make more.
Another full stack of cocks.
More!
Okay, that's it.
We're done.
Huh!
Freedom, baby!
With this spinning, we're gonna do something like that, I guess.
And then into a little boxy box.
Uh, make it vertical.
There.
Uh, turn it.
Yes.
Remove that.
Another vertical.
Boom.
Spin it.
I feel like this is the worst setup ever!
But, uh, you know, it works.
Let's try it.
One at a time.
No, two.
It ain't spinning, yo.
Is it working?
Oh, shit.
How come that's not...
connecting the way it should?
Oh, it is, it is, it is.
Bro, say...
I'm so confused.
There we go.
That's it.
And then vertical gearbox.
Uh, that one.
There it is!
Sweet!
Put all the pulp on there!
Yes!
While that's doing that, maybe we make more pulp!
Think I'm done making pulp?
No way, Jose.
Oh, we ran out of power already.
Dude, this thing is hungry!
It's actually so hungry, I don't even know if I wanna...
waste my coal on that.
Like, okay, hold on.
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop.
It's too hungry.
We have rotation right here!
We should be able to...
bring that out there somehow easily, right?
Like, look at this thing right there.
It's beautifully rotating.
Um...
Gotta bring that power somehow.
I guess we can use a vertical...
to...
Hey, what about this side?
Not spinning, okay.
Maybe here.
Ah!
There we go.
I got you now.
Now to find all the shafts I just made.
There they are.
Let's see where it makes sense.
In, down.
Yeah.
That makes sense.
So we don't even need this.
I guess we made a...
there.
Oh yeah.
Dude, this is...
this is gonna end up being so cool.
Like, when this whole thing is...
I don't know.
I just love it so much.
Look at the way we connect!
Oh!
The speed!
Yo!
Let's fucking go!
Tell me that isn't incredible!
Okay.
That's all done now.
We got cardboard.
I even have more cardboard.
Let's see what I can make.
Cardboard.
Helmet.
Pants.
Boots.
And...
chestplate.
I have expected an achievement...
for making all those, but okay.
Uh, okay.
So apparently...
Sneak to activate an inconspicuous...
Ooh!
Wait.
Are you saying I can sneak past enemies?
Maybe this is how I finally...
I'm gonna be able to pet cats.
Can I attack from the shadows?
Like a ninja?
Come here.
Oh!
What was that?
You see me!
Okay, okay.
I thought he was so dumb, he still couldn't see me.
Nope.
Nothing here.
Hey!
That's right!
Go the other way!
I'm gonna get in close and...
Yeah!
Who was that?!
They're blind!
Unless they get really close to you, they can't see you!
Look at this guy!
Okay, that's huge.
Guys, this... the cardboard...
future is here.
The cardboard age...
is here.
And it's here to stay.
That's amazing.
Love that.
In fact, I'm gonna keep it on.
I wonder though...
Let's say I aggro something and then I go like...
Oops!
Sorry, I didn't mean to.
Let's try.
Can I de-aggro someone with it?
My thoughts are probably not.
But let's see.
Nope!
You didn't see nothing.
That's crazy!
Hey!
Nope!
Nothing here!
Dumbass!
Oh my god, it's broken!
It's OP!
That's so good!
Also, it seemed like the arrow sort of bounced off of me.
When I had the cardboard on.
Or when I was sneaking.
Could be either because of the...
Wait.
Hold on, we gotta test something else.
Am I actually immune to arrows?
Arrow man.
Okay, the ultimate test.
Oh, he still saw it coming!
Is he gonna surprise me suddenly?
Oh, he saw me!
He saw me!
Ow, ow, ow!
Enderman?
Is he suddenly gonna pop up behind me?
I'm ready.
I'm ready to get jumpscared.
Nope!
Nothing's here!
Ha ha ha!
Do cardboard!
It's a new era.
Suck on that!
No way!
Ultimate Enderman!
Fighting disguise!
Dude!
Okay, you know what actually?
This is some next level shit.
We're gonna keep this cardboard on us.
Obviously we're gonna take a lot of damage from it.
But being able to just nope out at any moment is huge.
Massive.
Oh yeah, right.
I wanted to do something...
What was I...
Anything else with cardboard?
Now that I'm in the cardboard age.
I guess the cardboard sword is kinda funny.
Bound block of...
I think I made that already.
Wasn't really interesting.
Okay, yeah.
Cool!
Well that was nice.
What's happening out here?
Forgot to put this in.
I guess...
Can I use the pulp for other things?
Okay, so we can press it into that.
Okay, whatever.
Fine!
Let's keep looking.
Bamboo window!
Okay.
Doesn't even look like there's glass in it.
Birch window.
That could actually kinda look cool, I think.
Oh yeah!
So, look for anything green.
That was... that was the point.
So, obviously this, but I don't think that's relevant.
Pulp is kinda green.
Dude, I would think pulp, you know?
Oh, this super glue, man.
It's the only thing I need right now.
A linked typewriter.
Grants convenient control over many redstone link frequencies assigned to its...
Okay, hold on, bro.
That's too much for me.
I can't even...
process that right now.
There's, like, surprisingly little green things in this game.
Green dye.
We can make green dye.
I got a cactus and everything.
Never mind, I don't.
Where was I?
Oh!
Don't fucking tell me I need a slime bo...
I will never make a lead in my life.
It is too valuable for that.
There's just no way.
I kinda want these.
Prismarine.
Bulk haunting.
Aw, man, why...
Why is honey glue not the same?
That's so sad.
Shitballs, man!
Whatever.
Can I do anything with lily pads?
Or maybe...
Let me just pull a bunch of stuff.
I guess I... You know what?
Fine, let's make this.
Start unlocking things.
Unlocking things cannot be bad.
That looked interesting!
Hot air burner!
I guess for a balloon?
Oh, okay!
Very nice.
This is what I mean!
Like, you gotta craft this...
Random shit, you know?
And then something happens.
Give me, uh...
This one, that one...
That one...
This one...
Moss carpet, why not?
And...
Put this money in here.
Let me make sugar.
Pink dye.
Uh...
Oh my god, I hate my inventory.
Ooh!
Put it all back.
Sugar is food, I guess.
Doot, doot, doot.
Doot, doot.
Uh...
Put this in there.
I never used a spout, actually.
The block of coal is surprisingly super important.
For certain things.
If I destroy this, I'm gonna get a lot of experience.
Okay, well...
I really thought the pulp would be the thing, you know?
That I would need.
I'm gonna turn this back into that.
Because I do want to keep my coal for now, it's kind of important.
Uh, okay.
What else we got here?
What about candles?
Who knows what'll happen then?
To make a candle, I guess I need wax?
Oh, that's what honeycomb is for!
Smart.
Alright.
Okay.
I guess...
colored candles probably not gonna make much of a difference.
We can put a candle somewhere.
Dude, I get so low to the ground when I sneak.
There.
Turn it on, maybe.
Yay!
Kinda looks like a face, doesn't it?
With a sour mouth and eyes.
Or...
one eye.
That's what I think of.
I think of the guy from, uh...
Super Mario 64.
You know the big...
guy made of rock that, like, goes...
When he falls down on the floor?
It kinda looks like him.
A little bit.
Oh, no, he goes...
That's the sound he makes.
Let's go feed some animals.
Maybe these guys will poop out some green goop for me.
Like, can I just, you know, boil their fat and make...
glue out of that or something?
Okay, everyone's been fed.
Great.
You know what I could do?
I could put a couple, uh...
feeders somewhere here.
That are...
powered by, like, maybe a water wheel or something.
And if they just happen to walk into range, they get fed.
And it is a little more automated than it is now.
I guess that could be a thing.
51 flint.
Wheat flour.
Can I use that for something nice?
Wheat.
Flour.
Wheat flour.
It's part of crushing wheel.
Oh!
If you put wheat...
Yeah, right, okay.
Bulk washing.
Turn it into dough.
I guess...
Hey, we can actually do that right now.
Hey, I got it.
The whole setup is here.
I'm trying to throw it all in, but I can't because...
I will sneak too low, you know.
What's wrong?
You need more water?
You got plenty of water!
What's wrong?
Is it spinning too fast, maybe?
Wait, maybe I saw it wrong.
Flour.
Mixing.
No heating required.
Thousand millibar.
Wait, what's the difference between these two?
Oh, this one is a water bucket.
Wait, wait, are you saying that I literally need to...
And then put this in?
Oops, I missed it.
What?!
That's the way that works?
That's crazy.
Oh!
I saw green...
Slime!
Wait, you just take dough and make it green?
And you're like, this is slime!
It's like a little kid.
With Play-Doh.
Fucking hell, dude!
Lime dye.
Green dye, white dye.
Okay, okay, okay.
Green.
Dye.
How come I can't, uh...
Didn't I see that before?
Fuck, we need...
We need cactus?!
Or a large fern.
Okay.
Uh...
So we go desert.
Or we get a large fern.
Ooh, we're approaching...
The end game.
What does a fern look like?
Is that a fern?
How do I take...
Uh, maybe I need the...
Scissors.
Uh, da-da-da-da-da-da-da-da...
Uh, shears, I mean.
Maybe that's what I need.
Oh!
Short grass.
I think I just saw a fern.
There's gotta be other ways to make green dye.
Like, what else is green?
Shouldn't be that hard...
Maybe...
Okay, let's go to the ocean.
And collect some stuff.
Seagrass?
Maybe.
What's that?
I think seagrass, as well.
Uh, I mean, okay, we can look for a fern.
But I don't even know what a fern looks like.
Maybe just grass and steroids, you know?
Like a big grass.
I can't believe you take dough...
And just color it green, and pretend that it's now goop.
That is so funny to me.
We're gonna get all kinds of dye recipes now, because...
Who knows what it'll unlock, you know?
Okay, so I don't think this biome supports fern.
Oh!
No, that's not fern.
But it's green.
Shit!
What if I were to chop you with this, huh?
Teach you not to run with...
Oh, actually...
Dude!
Cardboard is not very protective, it seems.
I'm not here.
I'm a frogman.
Goodbye.
You've seen nothing.
Okay.
Okay, I think the fern dream is dead.
At least right here.
We gotta go to a whole other land.
In fact, I don't even know where I've seen a desert in this world at all, if I've even seen one.
The search for the glue will never end.
Like, it's just one more problem after solving the last.
The glue is crazy.
There's gotta be a way to make green dye in different ways.
Okay, red dye.
Bunch of red colored things, great.
Maybe moss blocks, if I just squish it hard.
Damn.
We can blast this into the green dye, but why would it do that when I can do this?
Seems like a bad idea, doesn't it?
I do want to see what happens if I crush this.
Man, you go way too far down when you crouch with cardboard.
Okay, something's happening.
Maybe just got crushed into nothing.
It's not here.
That may have been completely demolished.
Huh.
Alright.
What if I put copper ingots in there?
That are already ingoted.
I think it may be gone.
Shit.
Okay.
No more random experiments.
We're gonna check the book first.
Yo.
One more experiment.
Imagine this causes a black hole and my whole base is getting sucked in.
Probably nothing happens.
I mean, it's not in the book, right?
Ah, okay, fine.
Whatever.
But hey, you haven't lived until you've crushed an ender pearl with a crushing wheel.
Am I right?
Green.
Oh, what was the other one?
White?
Die?
Why can't I...
White?
Die?
Oh, easy.
Bone meal.
Easiest die of my life.
But I wonder if I...
What if I combine...
Hold on.
Color theory.
What causes green?
Let me actually quickly Google color theory.
Color theory...
What mixes to make green?
Let's see.
Primary colors.
Combine equal parts blue and yellow.
Aha!
I'm not a fucking painter.
Let's see.
Blue and yellow.
I can make that.
Uh, wait.
Yellow...
Would be a flower, I guess.
A dandelion!
Oh, god.
We have those.
Look at that!
Okay.
That's another one here.
I have no idea if this will work.
And blue?
Sure.
Oh, didn't look like it.
Not look like it.
No!
Okay.
Well, it was worth a try.
Fine.
Let's go find a damn fern.
And if we get assaulted by enemies, I'm just gonna sneak my way out of it.
Did I bring my scissor?
I did.
I'm gonna chop off your uterus!
That's evil.
Don't do that.
Is that a fern?
Guys, we're gonna play a game of is that a fern.
I get three chances to get it right.
Don't confuse this with is that my fern?
That's something else.
Is that a fern?
Number one?
This may just be tall grass!
Wait, I take it back.
It doesn't count.
Okay, wait.
I committed.
I have to, I have to.
It's not a fern.
Short grass.
I mean, this is kind of a different biome.
I have no memory of seeing ferns.
Ever in this game.
Something else that's green.
I mean, I should be picking up everything that's green, just in case we can make green die.
This biome is not it.
Nope, that's a dead end.
But honestly, I also want to find a desert.
Because that's like, that's a surefire way to get green die.
Because we get cactus.
And that should be pretty easy.
Maybe there's only two ways of making green die.
It's all the same, man.
It's the same biomes.
I still haven't seen anything that would qualify as a fern.
Not even remotely.
I love the effect.
You look through the little two holes in the cardboard hat.
I'll take this.
I wonder if I find a green sheep.
If I can then take the green wool and somehow extract green die from it?
Maybe that's one way to do it.
Bro, I'm reaching the end of the world here.
The desert?
Oh, it's a fake desert.
Shit.
Also called a beach.
I left my boat at home.
I'll make one on the fly.
Man, this is all the same.
Let's just go mega north.
Mega northwest.
North by northwest.
That's what we're gonna do.
So like this way.
The search...
for green.
I feel like that is everything I've been doing today.
The search for green.
And everything in between has been in aid of that search.
Oh!
What do we got here?
Something for me to explore and rob.
I like obsidian.
I take it.
Actually, I don't want this.
Keep it.
We can make obsidian powder out of that!
Uh, wait, what was I?
Okay, this way.
In fact, right over here, I think, or there, is where the stronghold is.
Oh, I thought for a second that was a cactus, man.
I got bejazzled.
That...
I've been there.
The hell was I doing over there?
Dude, imagine...
If you actually hadn't been there.
And you saw that.
You know?
Like there's someone in your world.
Somewhere.
Doing something.
That's fucked up.
That's legitimate...
Scary.
...stuff.
Like he's out there, you know?
Sometimes you'll hear him.
Outside your window.
The familiar sound.
Doot, doot, doot, doot, doot, doot, doot, doot, doot, doot, doot.
You know?
Nightmare fuel.
Is that another portal?
Fucking hell.
I have eyes of a...
Hawk!
American Hawk.
Man, there's no desert.
It's actually crazy.
I have to...
Travel this far to get some green fucking dye.
But it is what it is.
The things you do for...
Glue, you know?
Once you become addicted to glue, you...
It's hard to stop.
Once it's been up there, it's hard to get it out.
Or off.
I'm gonna skirt the outside here.
Like, I'm definitely getting a little lost on this trip, but that's okay.
We got a compass.
That's a lot of colors.
Except the color I need.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Those are some really large...
Plant thingies.
But I think they're just large grass.
Whoa!
Wait a minute.
This one.
Viridium.
Really?
I thought at least I could maybe crush that in a wheel.
Alright.
I think I've been here.
And the way I know is because the world isn't loading anything new.
I can feel it, you know?
Usually it lags.
I'm starting to think ferns don't exist.
They're made up.
What about this place?
Nothing.
Like, all these grasses look the same.
There's no fern-looking thing.
I think it's as simple as finding the right biome.
To be honest.
I think in these, uh...
Standard...
Wait, maybe kelp?
A desert would hit the spot right now, man.
Holy f- What's up with that island?
Look at the balance!
Hold on, I need a screenshot of that.
Beautiful.
It's like those rocks in...
Utah or whatever.
You know?
The ones that are balancing on a little point.
And they've been balancing for millions of years.
Something like that.
Little village near the snow and ice.
Doubt those ferns over there, but we can take a look.
In fact...
How about I bring home some ice?
I've yet to see what that does with create.
That's something we should do.
That could be kinda huge, actually.
Oh, I hate this island more and more the more I look at it.
It's terrible.
Look!
Wait, is it floating?
I thought it was like a semi-crime, but it's a full-blown crime.
Dude, this village looks so nice.
Look at it, nestled into the...
area there with the smoke coming up.
Do love that.
Is that normal grass?
Maybe hardened grass.
Against the frosty weather.
Of this... region.
Hey guys!
You don't happen to have any green dye now, would you?
Back here.
Show me the dye!
Oh, nice.
Saddle.
Got dyes.
Oh!
They fucking have a fern in a box!
Wait.
I have to crush it!
Right.
Okay, so that's what it looks like.
Wait, what does it look like?
Fuck me!
No!
I destroyed it!
Wait, that must mean they have...
The local area must...
What?
There it is!
Is that a fern?
Oh my god, it's everywhere!
We're so back!
I thought it was over.
Oh, the land of fern.
Yes!
I never even noticed these ferns before!
Like, this is whole new territory!
The ecology is crazy!
Beautiful!
I'm bringing home so much!
Dude, it...
It's everywhere!
Have I been in here?
I've been in there.
What's that?
Okram!
What the hell?
Wait, there's no way.
It's not even in here?
Huh.
Ok then.
What's that?
Oh, dripstone block.
Ok, uh...
Not interesting.
Why are things on fire?
Oh, that's why.
Hmm...
What's that?
Oh, it's path.
It looked different.
Uh, we need more ferns.
Think I'm done collecting ferns?
You're wrong.
I'm gonna...
Wait, maybe I can grow my own ferns!
So, wait, wait.
This one...
Has one?
Has two!
Ah!
Dude, we're gonna grow our own ferns.
I will murder your cows.
Why would you imprison little Timmy?
No!
Evil bastards that live here?
I will snip off your balls.
Hehe.
Wait, did it just burn from that?
I hate those plants.
I'll take this.
No, I don't.
I'm done, I'm done.
I'm out.
We made it.
Approximate home direction?
That way.
Easy peasy, we got it, man.
I can't wait to crush the shit out of this in my crushing wheel.
And the best part is...
It's gonna produce a lot of green dye.
Because we're gonna get like two to three.
Every time we put in one fern.
We're also gonna grow our own ferns.
In fact, I'm gonna make a fern pie.
And I will eat that fern.
I'm even gonna put a fern in my ear.
Both ears.
You've seen the cardboard outfit.
Wait till you see the fern outfit.
I guess that's just a ghillie suit.
Which is what the cardboard suit kinda is, if you think about it.
Now begins the long trek home.
Wish I had my elytra.
Ooh, wait a minute.
I was like, should I bring some villagers with me?
But there is a village closer to my home that I can use for that.
Because we're gonna kidnap some villagers.
That's the next step to get mending.
On the elytra.
Because before that, it's not gonna happen.
Yep.
And to do that, we need leads.
And to get leads...
You guessed it.
We gotta murder Stuart's favorite friends.
That's like the cost-efficient way of doing it.
But I guess now that we have access to all this green goop...
We can just make it ourselves.
It's not even that big a deal anymore.
We have infinite fern now.
And all we need is some, you know...
Spider webby.
And then we're cooking.
Actually, it's all coming together.
So we can make leads...
Out of the green goop we get.
We get the villagers.
We get the mending.
We put it on the elytra.
We use the elytra...
To...
Well, do everything, basically.
It's gonna be much more comfortable.
The next big step, of course, is extending the railway.
And to extend the railway, we needed the...
Green goop!
It's all coming together!
Like, can you just imagine the railway going through a mountain?
You know, and then coming out with like a bridge here on this side and going...
Oh my god.
That makes me so happy.
The train is real.
And now it's like, fully realized.
It was just semi-real today, but now it's fully real.
Now, to make the train tracks, I have to remember...
What exactly is that needed?
Oh wait, it's complicated.
We need iron or sink.
Okay.
It's not that hard, actually.
It's fine.
We just gotta have a machine running 24-7.
Just pumping out those trails.
Tracks.
For trains.
And then we're cooking.
I'm trying to think what else I need.
So we make the tracks.
Obviously we need to make a digging machine again.
Because the last one broke.
Stupid...
Screecher.
Or...
Whatever this guy is called.
Uh...
Creeper.
Blew it up.
Very rudely.
And it was such a good machine too.
I think next time I make a digging machine, I'm gonna make it stylish.
It's not gonna be a piece of shit.
It's gonna be a polished piece of shit.
It's gonna look shiny.
And nice.
I have no way if I'm going home, by the way.
Okay, it looks like I am.
In fact, I think we may even be close to the stronghold.
Should be somewhere around there.
On the other side of that.
Whoa.
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
Maybe we kill these guys.
Actually, no.
With cardboard suit, maybe not a good idea.
They're gonna fuck me.
It's gonna be terrible.
Hey, look!
There it is.
Oh!
Yeah, that means we're close to the boats!
Because remember, I had to go...
That's why that was there!
At one point, I had to make something real quick before I went down.
Yeah, look, there are the boats.
That's the stronghold right there.
Hey, wouldn't it be easier to just go in there and teleport back?
Wait a minute, I'm a genius?
Holy shit!
This is amazing!
How is this not the best thing ever?
Oh god.
This is like some speedrun stuff.
I just jump... and last time we slept was at home, I'm pretty sure.
So everything's cool.
What a shortcut, though.
I may have just figured out the ultimate...
Uh...
fast travel system we can implement...
throughout the world.
I'm not gonna reveal it yet, but it's genius.
I need to think on it.
Uh...
Right, so we're ho- Stop climbing that.
Meridium.
I would say that's exotic.
But not really.
So I'm gonna put it in here.
The fern!
Ooh, we're gonna crush that!
Hup!
Ho ho ho!
Nice!
And now we need white dye.
Which means bone meal.
Bone meal.
We're gonna crush all of this.
Boop boop.
I think I just threw something else in there that I shouldn't have thrown in.
What was it?
No, it was...
Wait, what did I just pick it up?
Huh?!
Oh, I must have thrown in something I...
didn't mean to.
Oh, that's weird.
Odd.
What?
No, no, no, no, no.
Put it here.
Dandelion.
Puppy.
Let's also crush these while we're at it.
And check this out, man.
Lime dye!
And...
Dude, we need to make more dough.
It's dough time.
Dough.
Wheat flour.
Comes from wheat.
It makes sense.
All in.
I'm all in.
He's all in.
Hey, we have three left.
Boop boop boop.
Now we throw all this in the water.
And then we throw a whole ass fucking metal bucket in there too.
Cause logic makes sense.
I wonder if the bucket gets consumed in this process.
Like, you would think empty the bucket, right?
Cause the whole basin here is kind of a bucket.
Nope.
It's the bucket.
The bucket goes in.
Maybe I get an empty bucket back out actually.
Sweet.
And now dough time.
Oh, dough is just...
Dough.
Wait.
Is it just simply crafting it?
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
What's happening here?
I can bulk wash it.
I mean, that's one way.
Oh!
Wait!
Hold on a minute.
Is it...
No, I don't understand.
Wait, did it just make two doughs just now?
Wait, I...
I don't under...
This makes no sense.
Mixing.
There's water in there and there's wheat flour.
Why won't it make dough?
Hello?
Like, something's going on.
Where are my buckets?
Okay.
Yeah, I'm also losing buckets, by the way, if I throw a whole bucket in there.
There's no way I'm...
Frickin' putting iron in my...
In my...
In my bread.
Huh?
Makes no sense.
I guess we're gonna bulk wash.
Something's off here, man.
It's not working.
I feel like the UI is lying to me a little bit.
I think I used my one and only fan.
Propeller.
Andeside and shaft.
Prop.
Andeside and iron sheet.
Oh, man.
I used all my andeside, didn't I?
Alright, I can just right click, I guess.
Yeah.
At least that's working.
Quite fast, too.
If I may add.
This is very confusing.
I must have some andeside somewhere.
Yes, I do.
Good.
Now to make a prop.
And then...
Fan.
And I'm guessing this needs to be rotated from...
The back?
Yep.
It also makes total sense.
Now...
A good spot for this...
Is this rotating here?
It is.
I'm gonna steal that rotation.
Actually, I'm gonna...
Create a vertical situation.
As time goes on, the whole house becomes more and more embedded in spaghetti.
This is the way.
Aqua affinity on that one, that's funny.
Not today.
And...
I guess crafting table...
Okay, good enough.
With that said, uh...
Then I needed to...
Bring a vertical.
There.
That goes down in...
I need some kind of block now.
Let's see what we have in construction.
Copper grate.
Let's use those.
Actually, no.
Man, I kinda...
Don't wanna destroy this.
Okay, whatever.
That looks kinda cool.
I... I... I can dig that.
Bring it down.
Then into another vertical.
Into a fan.
Spinning.
And the way we do this now...
Is we do that.
We do this.
And then we have...
Let's do some flapjacking.
Always good times.
Ah, wait, the...
It's...
Oh...
Hold on.
Gets blown away.
I wanna stop the thing from...
Oh, wait, we need water!
Almost forgot about the water.
Can't wash without water.
I have an idea.
Why don't we just utilize this water right here?
You know what I'm saying?
There.
Man, I...
Where's my dirt?
There.
Oh.
Vertical.
It be spinning!
Now we do a grate here.
And...
That's where we...
Wash.
Ah, crap.
I can't get out.
It's so awkward with the...
Why can't I jump out of here?
You know?
I mine way too fast.
Like, I'm destroying blocks left and right.
There we go!
That's it!
Now, we should also have a way to easily get things out of there.
And I'm thinking maybe a belt.
Right?
Maybe we belt it or...
It goes into a hopper, into a chest.
Now, a hopper is actually kinda dangerous.
Because then all the items are gonna fall down as soon as I plop them in.
Oh, look at the way this thing is immediately rusting.
Because of the water, I guess.
So, it's getting washed.
And as soon as it's washed, I think we need a filter.
Yeah, a filter would be the thing.
Maybe an andesite funnel or something.
But honestly, for now...
For now, it's okay.
Let's just do it manually.
Let's see if this actually works and they become dough balls.
Man, it's taking a while here.
Wait, I...
Are they dough balls?
I think we're done.
Yeah!
Oh, here we go!
Green!
Oh wait, it's called...
Slime.
Beautiful.
Absolutely beautiful.
And now we can make so much glue.
Iron sheets and iron nuggets.
I even have it.
Incredible.
Glue.
Make...
Three.
Yes!
And now the train can become fully realized.
By the way, you like my little system here?
Grab it.
Out.
We...
Oopsie daisy.
Dance with me.
I'm ready to dance.
Kinda wanna cover this up as well.
Wait, that's kinda genius too!
Wait, that's even better.
Watch.
We put things...
Hold on.
We...
Put things in.
Washed.
Grab!
Hey, that's even better.
And it covers up the top so it doesn't look shitty, you know?
I wonder if we can put some grass or...
No, let's... no.
I don't know.
Okay, well, uh...
Train dreams are real.
Stop it there.
Good place to stop.
What do you think of that, huh?
I just came?
Oh, I see, you just...
I would phrase it differently if I were you.
GG.
Indeed.
Another flapjack...
No!
Another flapjack W!
It's just...
Massing those W's.
It has a whole library of them now.
Huge stream.
It was a big stream.
Six hours, actually.
That's because the first two I streamed...
Deadlock.
It didn't go too well.
Got my ass kicked.
But then I...
But then I got into Minecraft, where there's no competitiveness.
And, uh...
The only enemy is myself, you know?
Probably most important episode so far?
I would say it's up there.
The train is finally here.
Walking past all the ferns in the village.
Well, I saw them, right?
And then I got them.
But unless you're talking about a village earlier that I...
Where I could have gotten them much earlier.
That probably happened too.
I wouldn't even be surprised.
When you first arrived there...
Oh, yeah, yeah, for sure.
What, do you want to snip my uterus?
Not yours, just the cow.
I don't know, because it's fun.
Something about a guy running around with a pair of scissors just snipping uteruses.
It's so stupid.
You could have just waterlogged the copper crate.
What does that even mean?
Waterlogged...
The copper crate.
I don't know what that means.
It's funny because you had figured out dough in the OG first episode.
Did I?
I don't even remember, man.
That first episode has been stricken from my memory.
It was such a disaster.
That's why I started over, you know, because it was so bad.
It was cursed.
Oh, yeah, and I was drunk that day.
That's true.
I was drinking.
That's my excuse.
Don't tell me how to do things, please.
I'll figure something out in time.
Yeah, don't tell me anything.
I'm gonna figure it out.
It's just a matter of time, you know?
There's no rush on that.
Need more beer.
I actually haven't...
The last time I drank something while playing was probably...
Was it the first episode of Doki Doki or something?
I don't remember.
I don't actually drink that often.
It's really rare.
Can I tell you good morning?
You definitely can, if I can tell you good evening.
But I guess we should switch it so that...
You would say good evening and I would say good morning to you.
Because it makes more sense.
Watching was somewhat cured me of wanting to backseat streamers.
I mean, if the streamer wants it, then it's cool, right?
Different strokes for different folk.
Like, when I'm playing StarCraft or Deadlock, I welcome it.
Like, please tell me how to improve, you know?
It just depends on the game.
As long as you're having fun, then it's good.
How do I join every time you're about to finish the stream?
Because I'm a little silly bastard that always streams at times that don't make sense.
And that's on me.
It really is.
It's not you.
It's me.
Because I do tend to stream weird times.
And it's not consistent.
There's no schedule.
You'll...
It's just whenever I feel like it.
So I can't blame anyone for not catching it in time, you know?
Join the Wad Watcher Covenant.
Become one of them.
What's for dinner?
I don't know.
What's for dinner for you?
I haven't planned my dinner.
Although I have some frozen... or some... not frozen, but in the fridge.
Cordon Blow?
I think it's called... it's like a type of... I think...
Is it turkey?
Or maybe it's like... I don't know.
There's cheese in there.
And then probably some greens and stuff with it.
How do I even pronounce that?
Cordon Blow.
Cordon Blow?
Chicken with a cheese and a ham!
Okay, yeah.
That's it.
Oh, right!
There's ham in there.
Right, I never even thought about that, but that's true.
Makes you think, how did they even get it in there?
Fucking... technology is crazy.
Boughton Blow.
Good enough.
I've...
I've not done anything with aeronautics yet.
But I just unlocked something today that I think will be the first thing I do with aeronautics.
Maybe next time.
Cordon Bleu?
So it's French, so...
Bleu.
Okay.
Cordon Bleu.
Cordon Bleu?
I think that was way too French sounding.
The tank technically counts as aeronautics, does it?
I would say that counts more as, uh, the other thing.
Uh...
Create Simulate.
No?
Was the tank flying or not, guys?
I didn't see a flying tank.
Simulated and aeronautics are the same thing.
Well, there you go.
Okay.
Yeah, so I would say Simulate is probably more...
fitting.
Haha!
I could probably make it fly.
Maybe we make a VTOL.
You know?
You start with an air balloon, it goes up, and then when you're up in the air, you transition into a...
You somehow...
put away the air balloon, and you go, like, fast.
If you put the physics assembler on the floating island, would it sink?
That's a good question.
Honestly, I think it would float.
But who knows?
We'll find out at one point.
Also, maybe the balloon is now the answer to the question of, how do we kidnap the hotel?
No.
But first, we gotta find the hotel.
The trains have so much potential, doesn't it?
When I read about the trains in the game and the ponders, it just seems so...
like, thought through.
That's the thing that's also exciting me the most right now.
It is the train, for sure.
Just connecting these different events and making tunnels and bridges with the train gets me excited.
Or just the prospect of it.
This idea reminds me of XCOM Interceptor's launch.
But the interceptors don't VTOL, right?
They get sort of angled upwards and then they get shot out.
Have you done anything with the Sable mod?
No.
I think it was a prerequisite.
It was a dependency for create.
Hiding in the cardboard box was amazing, yes.
And I'm not even kidding, it may even be meta.
For me in this world, in some fights.
Like, it could save my ass.
And who knows, maybe I don't need a full suit of it.
Maybe I just need the head.
Don't tell me though, but I'll experiment, you know?
Because that way we could get some protection and some stealth at the same time.
Sable is physics engine.
Oh, okay, well there you go.
I guess you couldn't have the Simulate or Aeronautics without it done.
Finally some Metal Gear gameplay.
That's a stealth series, right?
I do want to play that game actually.
It's like a whole series and Kojima made it and I really like Death Stranding, so I think I'll like it.
And I do in general like sneaking in games.
I'm pretty bad at it, but it's still fun.
Can you make a motorbike?
Maybe!
Probably, it wouldn't surprise me if you could.
I mean, you can make airplanes and frickin' air balloons and tanks and cars.
Wouldn't surprise me at all.
Will you play the whole series?
That fully depends on whether or not I'm having fun.
If I'm hating the first game, I probably won't be playing it after that.
And of course I'll start with the first game.
I'm gonna play it in order if I do.
Vintage Story?
A lot of people ask me about that game, like they want me to play it.
As far as I know, it's not finished.
Like it's still in early development or early access or whatever.
I will never revisit Terraria.
Unless they make a Terraria 2 and it's nothing like Terraria.
And it's more like Detroit become human.
In that case, I'll play it.
Okay guys, I'm out of here!
I'm gonna figure out what to make for dinner, actually.
I think I'll just go to the store and be inspired.
I go to the store every day anyway, you know.
It's good to get a little bit of...
fresh air and stuff, so...
Thank you for watching!
We are getting closer and closer to the day where trains...
are...
fully enveloping my Minecraft world.
And it's gonna be glorious.
Thank you for watching.
Have a wonderful Monday.
And I wish you the best week of all time.
Bye bye!